Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the NDN Community Meeting,
大家早上好，欢迎参加NDN社区会议，
hosted by NIST as a two-day virtual event with an exciting
由NIST主办的为期两天的线上虚拟活动，内容精彩纷呈，
agenda made up of seven technical sessions, two or
议程包括七个技术会议、两个或
three panels, and the posters and demonstration.
三个小组讨论会，以及海报和演示。
The agenda details and abstracts of all presentations are available under
议程的详细信息和所有演讲的摘要可以在下方找到
the Agenda tab on the Events page, as shown here, in this slide.
事件页面上的议程标签，如此幻灯片所示。
And the NDN Community Meeting is organized
与NIST和NDN联盟合作组织的NDN社区会议。
in collaboration with NIST and the NDN Consortium.
与NIST和NDN联盟合作。
And as some of you may know, this year, we completed the transfer
而且正如你们中的一些人可能知道的，今年，我们完成了转移
of the NDN consortium management from UCLA to NIST.
的NDN联盟管理从加州大学洛杉矶分校转移到了美国国家标准与技术研究院。
It happened earlier this year, and the consortium will play the role of single
今年早些时候发生的，联盟将扮演单一的
point of collaborative participation for industry, universities,
行业、大学的协作参与点，
government agencies and others interested in NDN to be connected and
政府机构以及其他对NDN感兴趣的人士可以连接并参与NDN的研究和开发。
to participate in NDN research and development.
参与NDN的研究和开发。
It will also provide general support of the NDN effort especially for
它还将为NDN项目提供特别的一般支持，尤其是为了
outreach communication and open source development.
开展外联沟通和开源开发工作。
This will work with the NDN community to address and standardize NDN and
这将与NDN社区合作，解决并标准化NDN以及
have the industry evaluate the technology.
有业界评估这项技术。
And as some of you know, we have a number of efforts,
正如你们中的一些人所知，我们有许多努力，
one of them being the NDN-DPDK forwarder that some of you are using,
其中之一是一些人正在使用的NDN-DPDK转发器，
and we have some ongoing work on NDN measurement and management.
我们还在进行一些关于NDN测量和管理的工作。
A template CRADA, Cooperative Research and Development Agreement, is ready.
一份合作研究和开发协议（CRADA）的模板已经准备好了。
It has been developed and signed by NIST and UCLA.
它已由美国国家标准与技术研究院（NIST）和加州大学洛杉矶分校（UCLA）共同开发并签署。
And I'd like to take this opportunity to thank the UCLA
并且我想借此机会感谢加州大学洛杉矶分校
team who took care of the consortium management when it was hosted at UCLA,
团队在它托管在加州大学洛杉矶分校期间负责联盟管理工作，
in particular Lixia Zhang and Jeff Burke.
特别是Lixia Zhang和Jeff Burke。
And I think Jeff is on the line and
我想Jeff也在线上，
then the probably wants to say a word here, Jeff?
那么Jeff可能想在这里说几句话，对吗？
>> Sure, yeah, thanks.
当然，是的，谢谢。
So the consortium, the mission is essentially the same
所以该财团的使命基本上是相同的。
as the consortium that was started by the academic institutions, but
作为由学术机构发起的财团，但是
with the hope that by hosting it at NIST, it will have sorta increased
希望通过在NIST举办，它将某种程度上增加
administrative stability and reached the work with government and
行政稳定性，并与政府合作达成了工作协议。
industry partners, as well as number of nonprofits and universities.
行业合作伙伴，以及许多非营利组织和大学。
So we're excited to complete the transfer and ready to
因此，我们很高兴完成转移，并准备好
start publishing new information about the consortium and get organizations aboard.
开始发布关于财团的新信息，并让组织加入。
Based on feedback, we've created a new fee structure for the voting members that
根据反馈，我们为投票成员创建了一个新的费用结构，以便
wish to be able to voting key decisions regarding the direction of the consortium
希望能够对财团发展方向的关键决策进行投票。
that's listed here on the slides including a reduction of the fee remission in this
这里在幻灯片上列出的内容包括减少本次费用减免。
pilot fiscal year in light of the challenging global circumstances.
试点财政年度考虑到全球形势的挑战。
Also, there's an opportunity for especially oriented towards nonprofits and
此外，尤其面向非营利组织的机会也有所提供，
universities to provide in-kind contributions of equivalent value that
允许大学提供等值的实物捐助，以此
allow voting participation through in-kind contributions.
允许通过实物捐助参与投票。
It's also a mechanism for industry partners to provide services or
这也是行业合作伙伴提供服务或支持的一种机制。
support to the consortium for some reduction of the cash fee.
支持财团以减少现金费用的形式。
So hopefully this provides more flexibility for
所以希望这能提供更多的灵活性给
a large number of organizations to participate.
参与的大量组织。
If we can go to the next slide.
如果我们可以转到下一张幻灯片。
So hopefully in time for a ACM ICN, you should see the release of
所以希望在ACM ICN会议前，您应该能够看到发布
a new identity for the consortium, as well as a civilian
一个新的财团身份，以及一个民用
friendly website that makes the case for the the technology,
一个友好的网站阐述了该技术的优势。
the consortium, the ongoing research that's continuing around the world.
该联盟，正在全球范围内持续进行的研究。
And so, this is a little bit of a teaser of the identity and we should have that
这是关于身份的一个小预告，我们应该会在
up for people to start taking a look at towards the end of the month.
在月底时，人们就可以开始着手查看了。
So we're excited about that, as well.
所以我们对此也感到很兴奋。
That's it for me, thank you.
我就说到这里，谢谢。
>> Thank you, Jeff.
谢谢你，杰夫。
Back to the agenda.
回到议程上来。
For the posters and demo session this afternoon, we have seven
对于今天下午的海报和演示环节，我们有七个
with two groups in the same BlueJeans Room because they have the same presenter.
因此有两个小组使用同一个BlueJeans房间，因为他们有同一个演示者。
So we have a total of six BlueJeans links as shown in this table.
所以我们总共有六个BlueJeans链接，如下表所示。
They will each have a short presentation at the lightning talk session.
他们每个人都将在闪电演讲环节进行简短的报告。
But four of them have provided the longer pre-recorded version of the thoughts
但其中四人提供了他们想法的较长版预录视频。
that we made available online at this link here.
我们在此链接上线上提供了该链接。
And if you go to that link,
如果您访问那个链接，
you will see the four videos in the browser window as shown on the left.
您将在浏览器窗口中看到左侧显示的四个视频。
And when you click on one of them, the video will be streamed
当您点击其中一个视频时，视频将会开始流播放。
over at the end without installing any software on your laptop.
它使用视频流媒体平台iViSa，iCN视频流应用程序，无需在您的笔记本电脑上安装任何软件即可在最后观看完整视频。
It uses the video streaming platform iViSa, iCN Video Streaming Application,
它使用视频流媒体平台iViSa，iCN视频流应用程序，
developed at University of Arizona, which runs over the global and the untested.
开发于亚利桑那大学，运行在全球范围内且未经测试的。
And we should probably try to run NDN next time over NDN, as well.
我们下次也应该尝试在NDN上运行NDN。
For panels, we have two today moderated by NDN co-chairs Christos and Kathy.
今天我们有两个由NDN联席主席Christos和Kathy主持的小组讨论。
And tomorrow we have one moderated by Christian on lessons learned over
明天我们还有一个由Christian主持的关于过去十年学到的教训的讨论。
the last ten years.
过去十年。
As many of you know, this year 2020 is the ten-year anniversary of
正如你们许多人所知，今年2020年是我们迎来的十周年纪念。
the NSF Funded Agent Project, which started years ago in 2010.
在2010年开始的由NSF资助的代理项目。
Before I hand it to Susmit for session one,
在我将它交给Susmit进行第一环节之前，
I'd like to thank the co-chairs, Christos and Kathy,
我想感谢联合主席Christos和Kathy，
the panel chairs, and the panelists, the session chairs, and all the presenters.
感谢小组主席、小组成员、会议主持人以及所有的报告人。
And thanks also to Debbie and for their help with the local arrangement.
还要感谢Debbie以及他们在当地安排上的帮助。
Finally, just one reminder about Q&A.
最后，关于问答环节，我想提醒大家一件事。
You could use either the chat window shown in this picture,
您可以使用这张图片中显示的聊天窗口，
or the raise hand feature.
或者使用举手功能。
And the chair will pick from both the chat and the raise hand list.
主持人将同时从聊天和举手名单中选择。
With that, I think it's time to hand it to Susmit for
接下来，我想是时候交给Susmit来进行
session one on NDN Trial Deployments.
会议第一部分关于NDN试点部署。
Susmit?
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Thank you, Lofti.
>> 谢谢你，洛夫蒂。
Good morning, everyone.
大家早上好。
My name is Susmit Shannigrahi, I'm an assistant professor at Tennessee Tech.
我的名字是Susmit Shannigrahi，我是田纳西科技大学的助理教授。
So in this session, we're going to have four talks.
所以在这个环节，我们将会有四场演讲。
We are thinking about 10 to 12 minutes for the talks and then 2 minutes for
我们考虑每场演讲大约10到12分钟，然后留出2分钟用于
discussions.
讨论。
I'll be giving a reminder before two minutes.
我会在两分钟前提醒您。
So let me introduce this first speaker, Dr. Alex Feltus from Clemson University.
那么让我来介绍第一位演讲者，来自克莱姆森大学的亚历克斯·费尔图斯博士。
He received a BAC in biochemistry from Auburn University,
他从奥本大学获得了生物化学学士学位，
served in Peace Corps in Fiji Islands.
在斐济群岛服役于和平队。
And then completed advanced training in Biomedical Sciences at
随后在生物医学科学领域完成了高级培训。
Vanderbilt and Emory.
范德比尔特大学和埃默里大学。
He has performed research in artificial intelligence, bioinformatics,
他进行了人工智能、生物信息学的研究，
cyberinfrastructure, high performance computing, network biology, tumor biology,
网络基础设施、高性能计算、网络生物学、肿瘤生物学，
agrigenomics, system genomics, and bioenergy feedstock genetics.
农业基因组学、系统基因组学和生物能源原料遗传学。
Currently, he's a professor in Clemson University's Department of genetics and
目前，他是克莱姆森大学遗传学系的教授，
biochemistry and co-founder of practice AI, LLC.
他同时也是生物化学和实践人工智能公司的联合创始人。
He will be sharing his experience in publishing genomics data sets into an NDN
他将分享他将基因组数据集发布到NDN的经验。
testbed and integrating with cloud workflows.
测试环境并将其与云工作流程集成。
Alex, please.
亚历克斯，请。
>> Hey, can you see my slides?
>> 嘿，你能看到我的幻灯片吗？
Is it good?
它好吗？
>> Yes.
是的。
>> Hey everybody, so yeah, thanks for having me here.
大家好，是的，感谢邀请我来这里。
This is an honor actually to be the first speaker,
这实际上是一个荣幸，能成为第一位演讲者，
that's never happened to me before.
这是我以前从未遇到过的。
That's pretty cool.
这挺酷的。
But so I'm an end user, I'm a biologist.
但是我是一个终端用户，我是一个生物学家。
I'm trying to understand lots of different biological things.
我正在尝试理解许多不同的生物学事物。
I have an interest in cancer biology and agricultural genomics too, a lot for
我对癌症生物学和农业基因组学也有兴趣，这是一个很大的领域。
food security and health, human health.
食品安全和健康，人类健康。
They're both really important for human health.
它们对人类健康都非常重要。
And to do my work, I have to use, I'm working at the terascale, petascale, now,
为了进行我的工作，我必须使用，我现在正在使用太级、拍级的计算规模。
and I'll be working at the exascale I think before I retire,
鉴于数据集的指数级增长，我想在退休前我将会使用艾级的计算规模工作。
given the exponential growth of data sets.
鉴于数据集的指数级增长。
So NDN to me is a really important
所以对我来说，NDN真的很重要。
layer of storage where you can have data accessed by name and
层存储，你可以通过名称访问数据并且
not all the vagaries of repositories that you have to
不得不应对的各种仓库的变幻莫测
understand how to navigate to be able to get the data in the first place.
了解如何导航才能首先获取数据。
So anyway, this is an incredible opportunity to be part of this
所以无论如何，这是成为其中一部分的难得机会。
development.
发展。
I think it's critical for genomics and of course, other fields.
我认为这对基因组学以及其他领域来说至关重要。
My lab is, I just love biology.
我的实验室，我就是热爱生物学。
I'm sort of attracted to chaos, I think, and I just keep,
我有点被混乱所吸引，我想，我就一直保持着，
see how far I can expand things.
看看我能把事情扩展到多远。
But I study plants, animals, vertebrates, and angiosperms.
但我研究植物、动物、脊椎动物和被子植物。
And these are some of the organisms that I've studied over the years,
这些是我这些年来研究过的一些生物。
if I can get a pointer up here.
如果我能在这里得到一个指示。
And again, to do all this work, we have to do a lot of algorithm development.
为了完成所有这些工作，我们必须进行大量的算法开发。
We do a lot of workflow engineering.
我们进行了大量的工作流程工程。
We're doing a lot of stuff in the cloud.
我们在云端进行了大量的工作。
We have to understand CUDA and we have to understand bioformatics and
我们必须理解CUDA，同时我们也需要了解生物信息学和
all sorts of stuff to be able to get our work done.
需要掌握各种各样的知识才能完成我们的工作。
Because the problem is that biological measurements now,
因为现在的问题是，生物测量技术，
DNA sequencers are pushing us towards the exascale.
DNA测序器正在将我们推向艾字节级别。
We're in the terascale, most biologists are now for measurement.
我们正处于太字节级别，现在大多数生物学家都在进行测量。
And most people don't know how to deal with terascale when there's a terabyte of
大多数人不知道当有一太字节的数据时如何处理太字节级别的数据。
hard drive space on their laptops.
在他们的笔记本电脑上的硬盘空间。
So in my research we're using a lot of AI right now, actually a lot of image
所以在我的研究中，我们现在实际上正在使用大量的人工智能，确切地说是很多图像
analysis techniques to be able to deal with gene expression data.
分析技术来处理基因表达数据。
And there's a recent paper we published where we're actually taking data
我们最近发表了一篇论文，我们在其中实际上是在采集数据
from patients and integrating it with other data sets like tumor data,
从患者那里收集，并与其他数据集（如肿瘤数据）进行整合，
and in this case, kidney cancer data specifically.
在这种情况下，特别是肾癌数据。
And actually tomorrow at Clemson, there's a speaker, the patient,
实际上，明天在克莱姆森大学，有一位演讲者，那位患者，
is gonna be presenting at our department seminar about our work.
将会在我们系的研讨会上展示我们的工作。
Together, he's a collaborator that we're trying to draw targets for him.
我们正在合作，试图为他确定目标。
So we do a lot of that kinda work, a lot of personalized precision medicine work,
因此，我们做了很多那种类型的工作，很多个性化精准医疗的工作，
and with protected data sets and unprotected data sets.
和使用受保护的数据集以及非受保护的数据集。
And we also do a lot of work trying to understand root biology and how roots will
和我们还做了大量的工作来试图理解根系生物学以及根系如何
fix nitrogen from the air with a symbiotic relationship with bacteria.
固定空气中的氮素，与细菌共生关系。
This is an NSF-funded project.
这是一个由美国国家科学基金会资助的项目。
And I'm also very interested in training people how to use clouds or
我也非常感兴趣于培训人们如何使用云服务。
HPC in cloud systems to get their work done.
HPC 在云系统中用于完成他们的工作。
And I have a company called Practice AI, where we actually have scalable data
我有一家名为Practice AI的公司，在这里我们实际上拥有可扩展的数据
intensive computing training and we're open for business.
我们提供密集的计算培训，并且已经开始营业。
This is a big part of biology now.
这现在是生物学的一个重要部分。
This is database records from the NCBI, National Center for
这是来自国家生物技术信息中心（NCBI）的数据库记录。
Biotechnology Information.
生物技术信息。
Sequence read archive database is one database.
序列读取档案数据库是一个数据库。
They used to be mirrored in Japan and UK, and
它们过去曾在日本和英国有镜像。
it's no longer mirror-able, if that's a word.
它们已经不能再被镜像了，如果那算是一个词的话。
Because this is, just one of the databases has 44.2 petabytes of
因为这只是其中一个数据库就有44.2佩塔字节的
DNA sequence data and you know this will be exabytes.
DNA序列数据，你知道这将是艾字节级别的。
There's an exponential curve in the not too distant future.
在不久的将来，将会有一条指数增长曲线。
So we want to mine this data, we do mine this data.
所以我们想要挖掘这些数据，我们确实也在挖掘这些数据。
There's almost 7 million experiments now, for mining.
现在有将近700万个实验可以用来挖掘。
It's available to anybody in the world, right?
它对世界上任何人都是可用的，对吗？
And so we're trying to deal with this massive volume, and the cure for
我们正在努力处理这巨大的量，以及治愈……
cancer is sitting there at 6.9 million experiments.
癌症的实验就有690万个。
It's just connecting the right dots.
它只是在连接正确的点。
There's 478,000 species now with at least one sequence in these databases,
现在至少有478,000个物种在这些数据库中有至少一个序列。
they're just exploding with amazing, valuable information.
它们正迅速暴增，充满了惊人的、宝贵的信息。
This is one database.
这是一个数据库。
We're also pulling data from NASA's gene lab database,
我们还从NASA的基因实验室数据库中提取数据，
which has similar types of data, but at a different repository.
我们还从英国的Ensembl数据库中提取数据，我们也有社区数据库、激光器，这些数据库包含了类似类型的数据，但存储在不同的仓库中。
The Ensembl database in UK we pull from, we also have community databases, laser,
我们还从英国的Ensembl数据库中提取数据，我们也有社区数据库、激光器，
agricultural, genomic.
农业，基因组。
So the idea is to cut to the chase, that's the right first thing,
所以这个想法是直奔主题，那是正确的第一步，
is that we're putting data in a testbed.
我们正在尝试将这些数据放入一个测试环境中。
We're actually trying to put all of this data in a testbed.
我们实际上正在尝试将所有这些数据放入一个测试环境中。
Not at one time, but actually have pointers to the data to be able
不是一次性地，而是实际上有指向待处理数据的指针以便能够
to pull it in as users request it using NDN naming strategies,
将其按照用户的请求通过NDN命名策略拉取进来，
which I'll show you in a second.
我马上就会向你展示。
But this is kind of the overview of our compute environment.
但这大致上是我们计算环境的概览。
We're pulling data from lots of different repositories, local storage,
我们正在从许多不同的仓库以及本地存储中提取数据，
putting into the NDN testbed and publishing it there.
将数据放入NDN测试床并在那里发布它。
And pulling it into cloud systems where we work on campus HPC,
并将其集成到云系统中，我们在校园高性能计算（HPC）环境中进行工作，
traditional HPC, but also did a lot of work in Google Cloud.
同时也在谷歌云平台上进行了大量的工作。
And also some commercialized clouds like the Pacific Research Platform and
同时也有一些商业化的云平台，比如太平洋研究平台和
TACC have Kubernetes systems.
TACC拥有Kubernetes系统。
And we're pulling this data using some tools we've developed as part of our
我们正在使用我们开发的一些工具提取这些数据作为我们的一部分
NSF science project into PVCs in the cloud and
NSF 科学项目转入云中的 PVCs（持久卷声明）并且
running workflows contain everything we're doing here is containerized.
正在运行的工作流包含了我们在这里所做的一切，都是容器化的。
This is one example.
这是一个例子。
GEMmaker is sort of a standard procedure that you have to do to build or
GEMmaker 是一种你必须执行的标准程序，用于构建或者
process DNA sequencing information.
处理 DNA 测序信息。
It requires lots and lots of different containerized applications.
它需要许多不同的容器化应用程序。
It's really complicated stuff, but we've got this working pretty well.
这确实很复杂，但我们已经让它运行得相当不错了。
So we can run this at scale.
所以我们可以大规模地运行这个。
We've run this petabytes of data.
我们已经处理了这数千亿字节的数据。
So in the end, we're publishing data in NDN.
所以最终，我们正在NDN中发布数据。
We also, just yesterday actually, were able to publish from,
我们也在，实际上就是昨天，能够从……发布，
with collaboration with Cisco and Internet2 is helping too,
与思科和Internet2的合作也在提供帮助，
publishing in an hICM testbed too we have set up.
我们还建立了一个hICM测试环境用于发布。
So we're actually trying to do this in parallel and
所以我们实际上是在尝试并行进行这项工作。
I'd love to have testbeds with the same code running on the same nodes and
我希望能有一个测试环境，在同样的节点上运行相同的代码，
sort of as a lofty goal that we have.
作为我们拥有的一个远大目标。
About all of our, everything I have on here, all of our data,
关于我们所有的，我在这里的所有东西，我们所有的数据，
all of our code is open source, and it's all on GitHub.
我们所有的代码都是开源的，并且都托管在GitHub上。
And these are, if I put them on here, they're probably tools that actually work.
如果我把它们放在这里，它们可能是真正有效的工具。
A big part of we're trying to do is with the NDN is with some of the problems being
我们尝试通过NDN（命名数据网络）所做的很大一部分工作是解决一些问题。
addressed, one of them is the fair data principles.
所解决的问题之一就是公平数据原则。
So findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability.
所以，可发现性、可访问性、互操作性和可重用性。
And so there's a complicated diagram here, but
这里有一个复杂的图表，但是
the idea is you have data in different repositories, local storage, right?
这个想法是你有数据存放在不同的地方，比如本地存储，对吗？
And people want to keep their data as biologists for
人们希望像生物学家一样保留他们的数据，以便在发布之前有一段时间。
a while before they publish.
以便在发布之前有一段时间。
And so things like findability, you can't find stuff on people's hard drives, right?
所以像可查找性这样的问题，你是找不到人们硬盘上的东西的，对吧？
Finding it in public databases is very doable.
在公共数据库中找到它是完全可行的。
Accessing it can be tricky, and I've been working with NCBI databases for
访问它可能有些棘手，我已经使用NCBI数据库工作了
25 years and I still don't quite understand their schema.
25年了，我仍然不太理解他们的架构。
So learning the tricks to be able to pull data is important.
因此，学会提取数据的技巧是很重要的。
Interoperability, a lot of genomics data is in common file formats and and
互操作性，许多基因组数据都是以常见的文件格式存储的。
sometimes you have to preprocess it.
有时你需要对数据进行预处理。
We're putting a lot of preprocessed data into NDN, the NDN testbed.
我们正在将大量预处理过的数据放入NDN，即NDN测试平台。
And reusability is a lot of this data storage so
你可以重复使用这些数据存储，因为它们的可重用性很高。
you can go and reuse it, repurpose it for other purposes.
你可以去重复使用它，将其用于其他目的。
And so we're trying to address all these problems with NDN, right?
我们正在尝试用NDN来解决所有这些问题，对吗？
Especially the accessibility part is abstracting all the metadata weirdness and
尤其是在可访问性方面，我们抽象出所有的元数据奇怪之处并且……
putting it into here so you can extract it with names.
将它放在这里，这样你就可以提取出带有名字的信息。
One thing cool about biology data is it's organized, well, biology is crazy, right?
生物学数据的一个酷炫之处在于它是有组织的，嗯，生物学本身就很疯狂，对吧？
It's like the craziest thing ever, like we were trying to explain biology.
它就像有史以来最疯狂的事情，就像我们在尝试解释生物学一样。
But if you organize data by evolutionary principles, it becomes actually rational.
但如果你按照进化原则来组织数据，它实际上就变得合乎逻辑了。
And so we actually have hierarchies of data sets from different species.
因此，我们实际上拥有来自不同物种的数据集的层级结构。
Like armadillos and humans are both animals, there's a common ancestor
像犰狳和人类都是动物，它们有一个共同的祖先。
thought to be from animals and humans 60 million years ago.
被认为是6000万年前动物和人类的。
Find a time machine, I would go back and see if I could spot this little guy
找到一台时光机，我会回去看看能不能找到这个小家伙。
running around, probably sequence with genome too just for fun.
到处乱跑，可能还会为了好玩而研究一下基因组序列。
But we have relationships between the data sets, so
但我们的数据集之间存在关联性，所以
we can organize things by genus and species.
我们可以按属和种来组织事物。
Geno phylum in family order, I can't even do it right now,
门纲目科属，我现在甚至无法正确做到。
all the different levels of taxonomy levels.
所有不同的分类等级。
Which we have baked into our naming conventions,
我们已将其融入到我们的命名规则中，
as a natural way to name data.
作为一种自然的数据命名方式。
For example, there's over 4700 genomes we're indexing right now,
例如，我们现在正在索引的基因组就超过了4700个，
pre-processing for workflows.
工作流的预处理。
And we have a naming convention for them.
我们对它们有一个命名约定。
I won't go into all the details, but we're actually processing all of these and
我不会详述所有细节，但我们实际上正在处理所有这些内容，并且
publishing them right now into one place of access, named access.
正在将它们发布到一个名为“访问”的统一访问点。
All of the RNA expression databases, data sets out there if anybody knows
所有存在的RNA表达数据库、数据集，如果有人知道的话。
what RNA-seq is, we have a naming convention too based upon biodomain.
RNA-seq是什么，我们也有基于生物域的命名约定。
And then the different levels of naming, and we actually have a UI setup for
以及不同层级的命名，我们实际上已经为此设置了一个用户界面。
this to be able to search the names, and be able to get.
这样就能搜索这些名称，并且能够获取。
Really, what we're trying to do is deal with these endpoint unique identifiers,
实际上，我们尝试要做的是处理这些端点唯一标识符，
which means a lot to the biologists to be able to pull data.
这对于生物学家来说意义重大，因为他们能够提取数据。
We have a test, an NDN type report.
我们有一个测试，一个NDN类型的报告。
There were, I don't think we actually published yet.
我们好像还没有发布。
We're still it finishing it up about how we're actually publishing data
我们仍在整理中，关于我们如何实际发布数据。
into the databases.
进入数据库中。
This is one of the test nodes that we're using right now to be able
这是我们目前正在使用的测试节点之一，以便能够
to publish our data.
发布我们的数据。
And so we're able to have students now,
现在我们能让学生参与进来，
biology students who publish the data with help from people like Susmit and
生物学的学生在像Susmit这样的人的帮助下发布数据，以及其他真正帮助我们处理技术层面问题的人。
others who are really helping us with the technical aspects of it.
以及其他真正帮助我们处理技术层面问题的人。
And we're learning how to pull data, so we're focusing on the naming, and
我们正在学习如何提取数据，因此我们专注于命名，以及
pulling, and pushing into workflows.
提取和推入工作流程中。
And then a lot of the backend stuff, we ask the people in my lab, actually,
然后很多后端的事情，我们实际上是请我实验室里的人来做的，
we have a pretty interdisciplinary lab helping with this.
我们有一个相当跨学科的实验室帮助做这件事。
But the Indiana community has been fantastic in helping us try to get this
但是印第安纳社区在帮助我们尝试获得这个方面做得非常好。
working for us, because ultimately, we care about just getting the result,
对我们来说非常有用，因为归根结底，我们只关心最终的结果，
right, and not so much the process underneath that.
对，不太关心那些潜在的过程。
These are some test data sets that we have, or experiments.
这些是我们拥有的一些测试数据集或实验。
We actually have two key data sets right now.
我们目前实际上有两个关键数据集。
One is a human kidney data set.
一个是人类肾脏数据集。
It's about, well, 36x2 files,
大约是36乘以2个文件，
1.16 terabytes, but we also have a rice data set.
1.16 TB的数据量，但我们还有一个水稻数据集。
It's about 1.14 terabytes, almost 1000 samples.
大约1.14 TB的数据量，几乎有1000个样本。
A lot of genomes are there.
有许多基因组存在。
We're trying to plug in all the genomes into the testbed, as well as trying to get
我们正在尝试将所有基因组整合进测试平台，同时也在努力获取
lofty with a lot of our goals, and trying to get more data in there.
我们的目标很宏伟，我们正在努力获取更多的数据放进去。
This is real quick preliminary results here.
这里是非常快速的初步结果。
So this is downloading the rice data sets here.
所以这里正在下载水稻数据集。
This is time in minutes.
这是以分钟为单位的时间。
It's very fast to get them onto the computer that we're then we're gonna
将它们快速传输到我们随后要使用的电脑上。
publish them on with the publishing and pulling rates here.
将它们按照这里的发布和提取速率发布出去。
This is for almost 1000 data sets.
这是将近1000个数据集。
It's taken a long time, right, to be able to do this.
花了很长时间，对吧，才能做到这一点。
And we're optimizing right now.
我们现在正在优化。
And we've performed some experiments with caching,
我们还进行了一些关于缓存的实验，
where we actually did with using commercial Internet.
我们实际上是使用商业互联网来进行的。
This is using no caching, and this is first transferred, and
这是没有使用缓存的情况，这是首次传输，
the cache kicks in, and we get much, much faster pull rates from NDN.
缓存开始发挥作用，我们从NDN获得了更快得多的拉取速率。
And then so opportunities, we can talk about this after this.
然后就是机会，我们可以在此之后讨论这个。
But we can exchange ideas to work containerizing stuff, and
但我们可以交流想法，共同致力于容器化事务，以及
learning how to do stuff like put data on PVCs.
学习如何执行诸如将数据放在持久卷存储（PVCs）上的操作。
Other communities need to do this.
其他社区也需要做这个。
I think Edmund's gonna be talking about this.
我认为埃德蒙很快会讨论这个话题。
We need better tools for publishing data, and more optimized tools to make it.
我们需要更好的工具来发布数据，还需要更优化的工具来制作它。
Optimization is pretty key for us right now.
我们现在非常需要优化。
We need bigger places to host data.
我们需要更大的空间来存储数据。
We wanna host exabytes of data eventually, right?
我们最终想要存储数百亿GB的数据，对吧？
I wanna be able to post about 10 petabytes a day, it would be ideal.
我希望每天能够发布大约10PB（佩塔字节）的数据，这将是理想的状态。
Be bigger data lakes writing grants to do this kinda stuff right now.
目前，我们正在申请更大的数据湖项目的资金，以支持这类工作。
And we need testbeds to be able to test out these containerized solutions,
我们需要测试平台来测试这些容器化解决方案。
because if you do this in the cloud, you'll be broke.
因为如果你在云端这么做，你会破产的。
You'll be going to debtors prison real fast.
你会很快进入债务人监狱的。
And so we're using democratized systems like the Pacific Research Platform.
因此，我们正在使用像太平洋研究平台这样的民主化系统。
And TACC has a Kubernetes cluster that we're running a lot of our tests on.
而且德州高级计算中心（TACC）有一个Kubernetes集群，我们在上面运行了很多测试。
And with that, my team is highly interdisciplinary.
而且我的团队成员来自不同的学科领域。
Funded by NSF, Cisco has been very generous with money, DOE USDA,
由国家科学基金会资助，思科在资金方面非常慷慨，同样的还有美国能源部和美国农业部，
working with lots of institutions, lots of people to get this done,
与许多机构、许多人合作来完成这项工作，
trying to help genomics out to cure cancer and feed the world.
努力帮助基因组学研究以治愈癌症和养活世界。
I'll stop there.
我就说到这里。
>> Thank you, Alex.
>> 谢谢你，亚历克斯。
So are there any questions?
那么，有什么问题吗？
I have a question for you, Alex.
我有个问题要问你，Alex。
So you mentioned the support from Indian community.
所以你提到了来自印度社区的支持。
So can you elaborate on that?
那你能详细说明一下吗？
What kind of support would you like to see?
你希望得到哪种支持？
Is it optimization?
它是优化吗？
Is it better APIs?
它是更好的APIs吗？
>> I think for me, if you ask my students, they might say something different.
我认为对我来说，如果你问我的学生，他们可能会有不同的看法。
But it's optimization at this point, cuz we have it functional.
但这个阶段是在优化，因为我们已经让它运作起来了。
We can pull data into workflows.
我们可以将数据整合到工作流中。
And we're focusing on that integration, modifying the workflows to pull data in
我们正在专注于该集成，修改工作流以拉取数据。
from the network, as opposed to the file system on the PVC, like is shown here.
从网络中，而不是如此处所示的PVC上的文件系统。
And so we need to be able to do that publish and
我们需要能够进行发布和
pull faster, but I think we actually have the pieces now.
我们需要能够更快地进行拉取，但我认为我们现在已经有了必要的部件。
I think we just need to make it faster, yeah.
我认为我们只需要让它更快一些，是的。
>> Okay, thank you.
>> 好的，谢谢。
So there is no other questions, then I think we can thank the speaker.
所以如果没有其他问题，那我想我们可以感谢演讲者了。
Thank you, Alex.
谢谢你，亚历克斯。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢你。
>> So the next talk is by Edmund Yeh.
>> 所以下一场演讲将由Edmund Yeh主讲。
Edmund is currently a professor of Electrical and
Edmund目前是东北大学电气与计算机工程学院的教授。
Computer Engineering at Northeastern University.
他之前曾是助理教授和副教授。
He was previously assistant and associate professor
of Electrical Engineering Computer Science and Statistics at El.
叶教授曾是电气工程、计算机科学和统计学的教授。
Professor Yeh was one of the PIs on the original NSF funded Project.
叶教授是最初由NSF资助的项目的主要研究人员之一。
He served as as the general chair for ACM Sigmetrics in 2020,
他在2020年担任了ACM Sigmetrics的大会主席，
and will serve as the TPC co-chair for ACM MobiHoc in 2021.
并将在2021年担任ACM MobiHoc的技术程序委员会联合主席。
His talk today is Data-Centric Ecosystems for Large-Scale Data-Intensive Science.
他今天的演讲主题是“面向大规模数据密集型科学的数据中心生态系统”。
Hello, Edmund?
您好，埃德蒙？
>> Okay, hear me now?
>> 好的，现在能听到我说话了吗？
>> Yes, yeah.
>> 是的，嗯。
And we can see the slides as well.
我们也可以看到幻灯片。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太好了。
So great.
太棒了。
All right, so great pleasure to be here today.
非常高兴今天能来到这里。
And [COUGH] so I'll be talking about data-centric ecosystems for
我将会讨论以数据为中心的生态系统。
large-scale data-intensive science.
大规模的数据密集型科学。
And this is something that we've been working on the last couple of years,
这是我们过去几年一直在努力的事情，
actually.
实际上。
So data-intensive science, we're talking about some of the world's most exciting
如此数据密集型的科学，我们正在讨论一些世界上最令人兴奋的
research projects, including Large Hadron Collider, high energy physics.
研究项目，包括大型强子对撞机，高能物理。
The Large Synoptic Survey Telescope in astrophysics, and
天文物理学中的大型综合巡天望远镜，以及
Square Kilometre Array, and also genomics.
平方公里阵列，以及基因组学。
So there are many such examples of large science projects,
因此有许多这样的大型科学项目的例子，
collaborative projects involving many, many different institutions around
涉及到世界各地许多不同机构的合作项目。
the world, That has to handle large volumes of data.
需要处理大量数据的世界。
They face similar set of problems.
他们面临着类似的问题集。
These challenges that go through all of them
这些挑战贯穿他们所有人。
include How to index data, how to secure the data,
包括如何索引数据，如何保障数据安全，
how to store the data, how to distribute the data efficiently.
如何存储数据，如何高效分发数据。
And very importantly, how to analyze the data, how to learn from the data.
非常重要的是，如何分析数据，如何从数据中学习。
This is a common theme that goes through many, many of these different areas.
这是贯穿许多不同领域的一个共同主题。
One needs to coordinate the use of computing storage network resources.
需要协调计算存储网络资源的使用。
Which, while they're ample, is still quite limited compared to the scale of the data
这些资源虽然充足，但与数据的规模相比还是相当有限的。
and computation tasks that these applications face.
和这些应用程序面临的计算任务。
Now today, what's happening is, these experts in these various domains
如今，这些不同领域的专家
are dealing with these systems problems, often in isolation from each other.
他们常常孤立地处理这些系统问题。
So they've had to develop their own solutions to deal with these problems.
所以他们不得不开发自己的解决方案来处理这些问题。
And actually, a lot of these efforts are being replicated across these domains.
实际上，这些努力在这些领域中被多次复制。
And one can see a kind of stovepipe
可以看到一种“烟囱式”的情况
kind of situation across these different domains.
在这些不同的领域中可以看到这种情况。
And one might ask, well, why is this happening,
人们可能会问，这是为什么呢？
that these smart people in these different domains all have to develop their own
这些在不同领域的聪明人都必须开发他们自己的
systems to handle all of these problems?
他们必须处理所有这些问题的系统？
Well, one underlying reason is that there exists this gap
嗯，一个潜在的原因是存在这样一个差距
between the application needs and the existing networks and systems.
在应用需求与现有网络和系统之间。
So the current networks and systems focus on addresses,
因此，目前的网络和系统关注的是地址，
processes, servers, connections.
进程、服务器、连接。
And consequently, the security solutions that they have also focus on securing
因此，他们拥有的安全解决方案也集中在保护上。
data containers and delivery pipes.
数据容器和传输管道。
Whereas the applications actually care about the data.
而应用程序实际上关心的是数据。
And so this is a gap, of course, that's been identified
当然，这是一个已经被识别出来的差距。
also as a primary motivation for things like NDN.
但这个差距，我认为，也是像NDN这样的事物出现的主要动机之一。
But this gap, I think, is one of the primary reasons why you're seeing
但这个差距，我认为，是你看到的主要原因之一。
these systems solutions being replicated across these different domains.
这些系统解决方案被复制应用到这些不同的领域。
And so what we're focusing on is taking a data-centric
我们所关注的是采取一种以数据为中心的
approach to systems and network design.
方法来设计系统和网络。
And apply this approach to the large-scale data-intensive science area.
并将这种方法应用到大规模数据密集型科学领域。
So this approach, the idea is to provide system
因此，这种方法的理念是提供系统支持，贯穿整个数据生命周期。
support through the whole data life cycle.
支持整个数据生命周期。
From the data production, naming the data,
从数据生产、命名数据，
securing the data directly, to delivering the data using naming.
将数据直接加密，以命名的方式传递数据。
Therefore enabling scalable data retrieval, enabling in-network caching,
因此实现了可扩展的数据检索，实现了网络内缓存，
automated joint caching, forwarding, multicast delivery.
自动化的联合缓存、转发、多播传递。
We wanna develop a common framework that can support different application domains,
我们想开发一个通用框架，能够支持不同的应用领域，
and not have to replicate these efforts every time we have a new application.
而且不必每当我们有新应用时就重复这些努力。
And NDN is something that enables that, and
实际上，NDN就是一个能够实现这一点的东西，它
is in fact a very appropriate architecture for
实际上是一个非常合适的架构用于
solving these large data-intensive science areas.
解决这些大型数据密集型科学领域的问题。
So one of the first projects to take this approach is the SANDIE project,
所以采用这种方法的第一个项目之一是SANDIE项目，
SDN-Assisted NDN for Data Intensive Experiments, which started In 2017.
SDN辅助的NDN用于数据密集型实验，该项目始于2017年。
So the team consisted of Northeastern headed by myself, Harvey Newman,
所以团队由我自己，哈维·纽曼领导的东北大学组成，
a very influential physicist and networking physicist from Caltech.
以及来自加州理工学院的非常有影响力的物理学家和网络物理学家。
And Christos Papadopoulos from Florida State, and
以及来自佛罗里达州立大学的克里斯托斯·帕帕多普洛斯，
then transitioning to Craig Partridge after Christos went to DHS.
然后在克里斯托斯去了国土安全部之后，转交给了克雷格·帕特里奇。
And of course, and in partnership with other LHC sites and the NDN project team.
当然，还与其他LHC站点以及NDN项目团队合作。
The approach of the SANDIE project was to use SDN-assisted NDN to redesign the LHC,
SANDIE项目的方法是利用SDN辅助的NDN重新设计LHC，
the Large Hadron Collider high energy physics network to optimize the workflow.
我们开发了一种NDN命名方案，用于高能物理网络中大型强子对撞机的快速访问，以优化工作流程。
We developed an NDN naming scheme for fast access and
我们开发了一种NDN命名方案，用于快速访问
efficient communication in high energy physics.
我们在高能物理中实现了高效的通信。
We deployed NDN edge caches with SSDs in multiple sites.
我们在多个站点部署了配备SSD的NDN边缘缓存。
And we used simultaneous optimization of caching and
我们还同时优化了缓存和
forwarding to make the data delivery efficient.
转发以提高数据传输的效率。
Now, this is, of course, we're actually building a real system here.
当然，我们这里实际上是在构建一个真实的系统。
So the feasibility of an NDN-based data distribution system for
LHC数据分发系统的基于NDN的可行性
LHC was first demonstrated at supercomputing 2018 in Dallas.
LHC首次在2018年达拉斯的超级计算会议上展示。
And last year in Denver at SC 19, we show greatly improved throughput and
去年在丹佛的SC 19会议上，我们展示了大幅提升的吞吐量和
delay performance by leveraging a couple of things.
延迟性能的联合优化，这得益于几个因素。
One was the joint optimization of caching and
缓存和联合优化是其中一个因素。
forwarding using the VIP algorithm that was developed by Northeastern.
我们接着利用了由东北大学开发的VIP算法进行转发。
We then leveraged the NDN-DPDK forwarder which
我们随后利用了NDN-DPDK转发器进行了相关工作。
Lotfi mentioned was developed by NIST.
Lotfi提到的是由NIST开发的。
And we used an NDN-DPDK-based consumer and
我们使用了基于NDN-DPDK的消费者和
producer developed by Caltech.
生产者由加州理工学院开发。
And then we had a live demo at SC 19 over a transcontinental layer two demo testbed
然后我们在SC 19上对一个横跨大陆的第二层演示测试床进行了现场演示。
that was running from the SC 19 floor to Caltech to Northeastern to Colorado State.
这条线路从SC 19现场一直延伸到加州理工学院、东北大学再到科罗拉多州立大学。
We were able to achieve over 6.7 gigabits per second throughput
我们能够实现超过6.7吉比特每秒的吞吐量。
using a single thread between the NDN-DPDK-based consumer and producer.
在使用单一线程的情况下，介于NDN-DPDK基础上的消费者和生产者之间。
And we also showed in another experiment that, using the optimized caching and
我们还在另一个实验中展示了，通过使用优化的缓存和
forwarding algorithms,
转发算法，
we were able to decrease download times by a factor of ten.
我们能够将下载时间缩短为原来的十分之一。
So that was a very exciting demo that we had last year.
所以那是我们去年举行的一个非常激动人心的演示。
And this is a picture of the throughput that we obtained.
这是我们获得的吞吐量的图片。
You can see on the upper left-hand corner there,
您可以看到左上角那里，
the 6.71 gigabits per second throughput.
6.71吉比特每秒的吞吐量。
And by the way, assessment was very
顺便说一下，评估非常
much a part of that demo that we had last year in Denver.
非常是去年我们在丹佛进行的那个演示的一部分。
Now what is the latest development this year?
今年最新的发展是什么？
NSF has just awarded a new project called N-DISE.
美国国家科学基金会刚刚资助了一个名为N-DISE的新项目。
N-DISE stands for NDN for Data Intensive Science Experiments.
N-DISE代表用于数据密集型科学实验的NDN。
This is gonna start this year, and in some sense,
这将于今年开始，并且在某种意义上，
this is a continuation of the SANDIE project,
这是SANDIE项目的延续，
a much expanded version headed by Northeastern, myself.
一个由东北大学和我本人领导的大幅扩展版本。
And participating co-PIs, Harvey Newman,
以及参与的合作首席研究员，哈维·纽曼，
Lixia Zhang from UCLA, Jason Cong from UCLA, and
来自加州大学洛杉矶分校的张立夏，同样来自加州大学洛杉矶分校的康健，以及
Susmit Shannigrahi from Tennessee Tech.
来自田纳西科技大学的Susmit Shannigrahi。
In partnership with LHC, and other genomics collaborators such as
与LHC以及其他基因组学合作者合作，例如
Alex Feltus, who just spoke, and the NDN project team.
刚刚发言的Alex Feltus和NDN项目团队。
So the challenges for N-DISE, we had SANDIE for the last three years.
所以对于N-DISE的挑战，我们在过去三年里有了SANDIE。
But LHC, the data volume is gonna grow by another ten times due
但是对于LHC来说，由于即将到来的原因，数据量将再增长十倍。
to the high luminosity LHC experiment starting in 2027.
到2027年开始的高亮度LHC实验。
It's gonna be much increased data complexity, human genome data,
将会有大量增加的数据复杂性，人类基因组数据，
Earth biogenome data, is going into the exabyte range.
地球生物基因组数据，正进入艾字节范围。
So that's a part of this N-DISE project as well.
所以这也是N-DISE项目的一部分。
There's a need to use diverse computation, storage, network, resources.
需要使用多样的计算、存储、网络资源。
And our approach is to build a data-centric ecosystem to provide agile,
我们的方法是构建以数据为中心的生态系统，以提供敏捷的、
integrated, interoperable, scalable, robust, and trustworthy solutions for
集成的、互操作的、可扩展的、稳健的、可信赖的解决方案，用于
heterogeneous data-intensive domains in the manner that
异构数据密集型领域中的方式，就像我在演讲前面部分所描述的。
I described earlier in the talk.
我在演讲前面部分所描述的。
So the goal of N-DISE is to deploy and condition the first prototype
所以N-DISE的目标是部署并配置第一个原型。
production-ready NDN-based petascale data distribution, caching,
面向生产的基于NDN的千万亿级数据分发、缓存、
access, and computation system serving major science programs.
访问和计算系统，服务于主要的科学计划。
The LHC high energy physics program will be a leading target use case.
LHC高能物理计划将成为一个主要的目标使用案例。
But the other application we'll be focusing on is the BioGenome,
但我们将重点关注的另一个应用是生物基因组项目，
human genome projects And as future use cases we'll be looking at LSST, SKA.
人类基因组项目，以及我们未来将研究的用例包括大型光学巡天望远镜（LSST）和平方公里阵列（SKA）。
We'll leverage NDN protocols, high throughput forwarding caching techniques,
我们将利用NDN协议、高吞吐量转发缓存技术，
containerization techniques, as Alex was talking about in order to handle different
容器化技术，正如亚历克斯所说，以便处理不同
operating systems to be able to upgrade easily.
操作系统能够轻松升级。
Integrated with SDN techniques and as well as FPGA acceleration subsystems.
集成了SDN技术以及FPGA加速子系统。
So Jason Tong is an FPGA expert that's on the team.
所以Jason Tong是团队中的FPGA专家。
We're aiming to deliver LHC data over wide area network at throughputs near 100
我们的目标是通过广域网传输大型强子对撞机(LHC)的数据，吞吐量接近每秒100吉比特。
gigabits per second.
每秒吉比特。
That'll be our target achievable because of when we use, we're planning to do multi
我们的目标可达成，因为我们计划使用多线程实现，这将允许吞吐量线性扩展。
threaded implementations which is going to allow for linear scaling of throughput.
我们将通过使用多线程实现来显著减少下载时间，这将允许吞吐量线性扩展。
We'll be looking at dramatically decreasing download times by using
我们将通过使用多线程实现来显著减少下载时间，
optimized caching.
并且我们将构建一个具有高性能优化缓存的增强测试平台。
And we'll have built an enhanced testbed with high performance
我们将构建一个具有高性能优化缓存的增强测试平台。
NDN data cache servers.
NDN数据缓存服务器。
So how much time do I have left to spend?
那我还剩多少时间可以用？
>> About five minutes.
大约五分钟。
>> Okay, good.
>> 好的，很好。
So to go into the research agenda a bit more in detail.
所以，让我们更详细地进入研究议程。
So we had built the NBN-DPDK consumer and producer Caltech had done that.
所以我们已经构建了NBN-DPDK的消费者和生产者，加州理工学院已经完成了这项工作。
We're now going to look at developing multi threaded consumer and
我们现在将研究开发多线程的消费者和
producer applications to aim for linear throughput scaling.
生产者应用程序以实现线性吞吐量扩展为目标。
This is going to be integrated with a NDN-DPDK, XRootD plugin.
这将与NDN-DPDK的XRootD插件集成。
XRootD is the current redirector tool application that's used in LHC in
XRootD是目前在大型强子对撞机(LHC)中使用的重定向工具应用。
order for people to discover data and to map requests to different servers.
为了让人们发现数据并将请求映射到不同的服务器。
And so what we previously did in Sandy was to build a plugin that
我们之前在Sandy做的是构建了一个插件，它
allowed you to interface with an NDN networking system.
允许您与NDN网络系统进行接口对接。
And so this has actually been developed or now integrated with NDN-DPDK.
因此，这实际上已经开发或现在与NDN-DPDK集成在一起了。
And now we're going to integrate that with a multi threaded consumer producer
现在我们将把它与多线程的消费者生产者集成起来。
application.
我们将会研究用于NDN-DPDK的容器应用。
We're going to be looking at containers for NDN-DPDK and
other applications in order to handle diverse server requirements,
其他应用程序以处理多样化的服务器需求，
server equipment and interfaces.
服务器设备和接口。
We're looking at using docker containers so that we can host guest
我们正在考虑使用Docker容器，这样我们就可以托管客户端。
operating systems, enables easy state restoration, ease upgrading.
操作系统使得状态恢复变得容易，也便于升级。
We'll be looking at data integrity and provenance.
我们将会研究数据的完整性和来源。
This is we want to do data origin authentication.
我们想要进行数据来源验证。
So even though maybe security is not a huge concern in let's say LHC data,
所以即使在比如说大型强子对撞机（LHC）的数据中，安全可能不是一个非常大的问题，
authentication is a huge concern.
我们不仅想要验证数据的来源，而且认证是一个非常大的问题。
Not only do we want to authenticate to data origin, but
我们不仅想要验证数据的来源，而且
we wanna authenticate, we want to do authenticated traces.
我们想要进行认证，我们想要做到认证的追踪。
Because what happens in these applications is that the output data from one
因为在这些应用程序中发生的情况是，一个应用程序的输出数据将作为另一些研究科学家的输入数据。
group of scientists is going to be used as input data for other research scientists.
一组科学家的输出数据将会被用作其他研究科学家的输入数据。
So we want to authenticate, we want to do authenticated tracing as the data moves
因此，我们想要进行验证，我们想要在数据传输过程中进行认证跟踪。
through a multiple processing steps.
在多个处理步骤中。
So this will be extremely valuable for data scientists in this area.
因此，这对该领域的数据科学家来说将极其有价值。
And we're aiming to do this through data manifests where you compute hashes of data
我们的目标是通过数据清单来实现这一点，你需要计算数据的哈希值。
segments and then you sign the hashes.
我们想要使用一种叫做分段的方法来进行拥塞控制重传，然后对这些哈希值进行签名。
We want to do congestion control retransmission using something called
分段, 然后对这些哈希值进行签名。
NETBLT.
网络块传输协议。
Which, I think, developed many years ago, but we're gonna put it
它是多年前开发的，但我们打算要去实施它。
at the network layer so that we can effectively interface with caching.
在网络层面上，这样我们就可以有效地与缓存系统进行交互。
We're gonna be looking at advanced caching storage solutions.
我们将会研究高级缓存存储解决方案。
So we want to extend the VIP caching forwarding
所以我们想要扩展VIP缓存转发功能。
algorithm to interact with multi threaded borders.
算法与多线程边界交互。
We're going to look at hierarchical caching systems involving different types
我们将研究涉及不同类型的分层缓存系统。
of memory SSDs, Intel Optane for handling large data volumes.
的内存SSD，英特尔Optane用于处理大数据量。
So in these applications,
所以在这些应用程序中，
the volume is still huge that one has to exploit all kinds of
存储量依然庞大，人们必须利用各种各样的方式来处理。
storage one has access to and this requires a hierarchical caching system.
存储系统需要访问的存储量，这就要求有一个分层的缓存系统。
We want to use FPGA acceleration with so FPGA is known to be programming adaptive,
我们想要使用FPGA加速，因为众所周知FPGA具有可编程的自适应性，
it can give us a high throughput, low latency energy efficiency.
它可以为我们提供高吞吐量、低延迟和高能效。
The primary focus here will be to use FPGA acceleration to accelerate hash functions,
这里的主要重点将是使用FPGA加速来加速哈希函数，
lookups in the NDN-DPDK Name Dispatch Table,
在NDN-DPDK名称分派表中查找，
the PIT-CS Composite Table and also the FIB.
PIT-CS复合表以及FIB。
So, to wrap up the talk, so data intensive science applications such as LHC,
那么，总结一下这次讲话，像LHC这样的数据密集型科学应用，
Genomics and various other applications require fundamental
基因组学和其他各种应用需要基本的
network system solutions to address common needs.
网络系统解决方案来满足共同需求。
NDN provides such a common framework that data-centric
NDN提供了这样一个通用框架，它是以数据为中心的。
systems support that provides support through the whole data lifecycle.
它为整个数据生命周期提供支持的系统支持。
It's a natural fit for applications like LHC, genomics and
它自然适用于像大型强子对撞机(LHC)、基因组学等应用。
other data intensive applications.
其他数据密集型应用。
We've already shown in the SANDIE project that we can get
我们已经在SANDIE项目中展示了我们可以获得
very high performance with NDN.
我们可以通过NDN获得非常高的性能。
We should have throughput at 6.7 gigabits per second over wide area network
我们应该能够在广域网上实现每秒6.7吉比特的吞吐量。
using NDN-DPDK forwarder using the optimized caching voting algorithms.
所以关键是我们可以通过使用优化的缓存投票算法的NDN-DPDK转发器获得非常高的性能。
So the point is that we can get very high performance using
所以关键是我们可以通过使用
NDN approach to large scale data intensive science.
NDN方法应用于大规模数据密集型科学。
And the new project N-DISE, we're working toward the first prototype,
我们正在努力开发新项目N-DISE的第一个原型，
production ready NDN system, which is going to be integrated with SDN,
生产就绪的NDN系统，将与SDN集成，
with FPGA and containerization.
与FPGA和容器化技术相结合。
And of course, we're seeking long-term collaboration with various domain
当然，我们正在寻求与不同领域的科学家、网络计算机系统社区长期合作，以推动这一进程。
scientists, networking computer system communities in order to push forward this
过程。我们还致力于建立以数据为中心的生态系统，以支持大规模数据密集型科学研究项目。
project to build data-centric ecosystems for large scale data intensive science.
项目旨在构建以数据为中心的生态系统，支持大规模数据密集型科学研究。
Thanks very much.
非常感谢。
>> Thank you Edmund.
>> 谢谢你，埃德蒙。
I think Dave has a question for you or a comment.
我认为戴夫对你有一个问题或者想发表评论。
>> Am I muted?
>> 我被静音了吗？
>> No, we can hear you.
>> 不，我们能听见你。
>> Good, so you're calling something tracing.
>> 好的，所以你们把它叫做追踪。
Which I've always heard called Data provenance.
我一直听说这被称为数据溯源。
I'm curious if you think of it as something different or
我好奇你是否认为它是不同的东西还是
is this the same stuff that Margo Seltzer and
她的合作者们已经研究了10年的东西吗？
her collaborators have been working on for 10 years.
她的合作者们已经研究了10年的东西。
>> So I'm actually not aware of that to admit what you said but
所以我其实并不知道承认你所说的内容。
the idea here is to basically,
基本上，这里的想法是要……
essentially do a multistep provenance cell.
本质上要做一个多步骤的溯源细胞。
>> Yeah, right, right, right, right.
是的，没错，没错，没错。
>> So. >> There's like 10 years of
>> 那么。>> 大概有十年的
papers on this.
论文在这上面。
I think you people should look at it before you go invent something new.
我认为你们在发明新东西之前应该先看看这个。
>> Yeah, I didn't really actually mean to suggest necessarily it's a new thing.
是的，我其实并不是真的想要暗示这是一个全新的事物。
But we're just going to do that in the context of large scale data intensive
但我们将在大规模数据密集型的背景下进行这一工作。
science, I guess and within this ecosystem.
科学，我猜，就在这个生态系统之中。
>> That is really useful to talk to Margo about this.
这和Margo讨论真的很有用。
She's known at UBC because when I heard her last talk, she basically said,
她在UBC很有名，因为我听她上一次演讲时，她基本上是这么说的，
yeah, we know, pretty much understand how to do all this.
是的，我们知道，基本上明白怎么去做这一切。
The technical means of doing with multi signatures and
处理多重签名和技术手段
backward pointers and stuff like that.
后向指针之类的东西。
You know, we sorta know how to do it.
你知道的，我们有点知道怎么去做这件事。
What happened was when we tried to do this, the scientists hated it.
发生的事情是，当我们尝试去做这件事时，科学家们非常反感。
>> Okay.
好的。
Okay, so.
好的，那么。
>> So figuring out how to get the scientists on board with a data provenance
>> 因此，搞清楚如何让科学家们接受数据溯源系统在NDN下可能比他们在其他系统中发现的要容易。
system under NDN might be easier than what they've discovered with other systems.
系统在NDN下可能比他们在其他系统中发现的要容易。
>> Right.
对。
That's a good I mean, so you know, security and provinance has not been so
这是一个很好的，我的意思是，所以你知道的，安全性和起源至今还没有成为如此
far a major concern in the physics community just because I think that they
在物理学界，这一直是一个主要的担忧，仅仅因为我认为他们
Control access to their network very tightly.
他们对自己的网络访问进行了非常严格的控制。
At the moment, so maybe they don't worry about it.
目前，所以也许他们并不担心这个问题。
But I think in at least in other data intensive areas.
但我认为至少在其他数据密集型领域。
>> Our environment really, important.
>> 我们的环境真的很重要。
>> Yeah.
>> 是的。
>> Right. >> So we will have but yeah,
>> 对。>> 所以我们将会有，但是是的，
they probably they will need some convincing.
他们可能需要一些说服。
Yes, and that effort is just starting.
是的，而且这种努力才刚刚开始。
So we'll know.
所以我们会知道。
>> All I'm saying is that, anybody who's actually doing the technical
>> 我只是想说，任何真正在做技术工作的人
work to develop tracing algorithms, friend Deanne.
致力于开发追踪算法的工作，朋友Deanne。
What a review of the literature on data provenance.
对数据溯源文献的综述。
>> Okay, yeah.
好的。
Thank you, thanks for pointing that out.
谢谢你，感谢你指出那一点。
>> Thanks.
>> 谢谢。
>> Thank you.
>> Alright, thank you Edmund.
>> 好的，谢谢你，Edmund。
Flip the, flip the >> Next subject.
>> 下一个话题。
>> Our next speaker is Lan Wang.
>> 我们下一个演讲者是王兰。
Lan is gonna be a professor and
兰将成为一名教授。
chair of the Computer Science Department at University of Memphis.
兰将成为孟菲斯大学计算机科学系主任。
So, you will be speaking about M card,
所以，你将会谈论M卡，
secure, real time data distribution system,
安全的、实时数据分发系统，
with fine grain access control for, M health research,
具有细粒度访问控制的，用于移动健康研究，
the continuation of the discussion that we just had, planned.
我们刚才讨论的内容的后续，已经计划好了。
>> Yes, but how do I share?
是的，但我该如何分享呢？
I think admin needs to stop sharing.
我认为管理员需要停止分享。
>> Even start sharing just put you can push them out if you start yours.
>> 即使开始分享，只要你开始你的，你就可以把他们推出去。
>> Okay, See my screen
>> 好的，看我的屏幕
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Okay, good morning.
>> 好的，早上好。
I'm going to talk about a new initiative funded project mGuard.
我将要讲述一个由资助项目mGuard支持的新倡议。
This is a collaboration between me,
这是我与其他人合作的项目，
my colleague Santosh Kumar and Lixia Zhang at UCLA.
我的同事桑托什·库马尔和加州大学洛杉矶分校的李夏·张。
Today, many of us have smartwatches, smartphones, smart scales.
如今，我们中的许多人都拥有智能手表、智能手机、智能秤。
These devices monitor our heart rate, blood oxygen levels,
这些设备监测我们的心率、血氧水平、
sleep, weight, and various other biometrics.
睡眠、体重以及其他各种生物测量指标。
Such mobile health data, it can be used to
这些移动健康数据可以被用来
study a wide range of health and wellness issues, such as stress,
研究广泛的健康和福祉问题，例如压力、
sleep disorders, congestive heart failures, and migraine.
睡眠障碍、充血性心力衰竭和偏头痛。
But the data reveals a lot of our own private lives.
但这些数据透露了我们许多个人隐私。
So the privacy and security issues here,
因此这里的隐私和安全问题，
need to be investigated.
需要被调查。
But existing mobile health data infrastructure
但现有的移动健康数据基础设施
lack support for fine-grained access control.
缺乏对细粒度访问控制的支持。
For example, you can get access to a whole data set.
例如，你可以获得整个数据集的访问权限。
But you can they cannot control which users data you
但是你可以控制他们不能管理哪些用户的数据。
can look at which users data you cannot, they can also,
他们也可以查看你不能查看的用户数据。
they cannot enforce Access Control based on time or location either.
他们也无法基于时间或地点执行访问控制。
So that is a big constraint.
所以这是一个很大的限制。
Also, researchers cannot get real time
此外，研究人员也无法实时获得
many times, they cannot get real time access to the data.
很多时候，他们无法实时访问数据。
They are only send the data after everything is collected.
他们只有在所有数据都收集完毕后才发送数据。
But if you want to do real time intervention,
但如果你想进行实时干预，
then that's not feasible with current access.
那么用当前的访问方式是不可行的。
So we want to apply NDN's name based data centric approach to solve these problems.
所以我们想应用NDN的基于名称的数据中心方法来解决这些问题。
And because here we have
而且因为在这里我们有
NIH funded mobile health data center.
美国国立卫生研究院资助的移动健康数据中心。
So it's very natural for us to collaborate with this
所以我们与之合作是非常自然的。
NIH MD2K centre to work on this problem.
美国国立卫生研究院MD2K中心致力于研究这个问题。
So MD2K stands for mobile sensor data to knowledge.
所以MD2K代表的是将移动传感器数据转化为知识。
It is one of 11 National NIH big data centres of excellence.
它是国家卫生研究院11个大数据卓越中心之一。
It's led by my colleague Santosh Kumar.
它是由我的同事Santosh Kumar领导的。
Their mission is to develop tools, to gather, analyze,
他们的使命是开发工具，收集、分析，
and interpret health data generated by mobile and wearable sensors.
和解释由移动和可穿戴传感器产生的健康数据。
The, MD2K center, is a collaboration amongst
MD2K中心是多方合作的成果，
17 universities involving many faculty members,
17所大学涉及许多教职员工。
students and staff members.
学生和教职员工。
So they conduct many health related studies.
所以他们进行了许多与健康相关的研究。
And the studies produce a lot of sensor data and
这些研究产生了大量的传感器数据和
all the data is collected by the MD2K's enter,
所有数据都由MD2K的中心收集，
into a cloud based system.
进入一个基于云的系统。
And through the system, the study coordinators can
通过这个系统，研究协调员可以实时监控他们的参与者。
monitor their participants in real time.
监控他们的参与者实时情况。
The data science researchers can use the data to develop bile markers and
数据科学研究人员可以使用这些数据来开发胆汁标记物并且
validate the markers.
验证这些标记物。
And then the health researchers,
然后是健康研究人员，
can you use the bile markers to analyze their patients' health,
能否使用胆汁标记物来分析他们患者的健康状况，
and study the effectiveness of the bile markers.
并研究胆汁标记物的有效性。
This data has more than 2200 participants.
这些数据有2200多名参与者。
More than 100,000 participant days.
超过10万名参与者的日子。
4.7 trillion data points and more than 300 terabytes of data size.
4.7万亿个数据点和超过300TB的数据大小。
These numbers are from last year.
这些数字是去年的数据。
Probably the current data size is much bigger.
可能当前的数据量要大得多。
So, here's the proposed mGuard system.
所以，这就是提议的mGuard系统。
We don't want to change the existing system, we want to enhance it.
我们不想改变现有的系统，我们想要增强它。
So, we will continue to use the existing MD2K components.
所以，我们将继续使用现有的MD2K组件。
There are two major components.
有两个主要组件。
One is called M cerebellum?
一个被称为小脑？
It's a data collection platform composed of sensors and
它是一个由传感器和移动电话组成的数据收集平台，用于收集研究参与者的数据。
mobile phones to collect data from study participants.
移动电话用来收集研究参与者的数据。
And this platform will send data to cerebral cortex.
这个平台将会将数据发送到大脑皮层。
That's a cloud based system to store and support computing on the data.
这是一个基于云的系统，用于存储和支持数据计算。
And what we are going to do is to add an NDN data adapter that
我们将要做的是添加一个NDN数据适配器，该适配器将会对数据进行加密、签名并以NDN格式打包。
will encrypt sign and packetize the data in NDN format.
将会对数据进行加密、签名并以NDN格式打包。
And store the packets in MDN repo.
并将数据包存储在MDN仓库中。
And these two systems, sorry these two components will work on
这两个系统，抱歉，这两个组件将会运作在
top of NDN forwarder to send and receive NDN packets.
顶层的NDN转发器用来发送和接收NDN数据包。
That's on the server side, on the receiver side, the users can continue to use
这是服务器端的情况，在接收方这边，用户可以继续使用
their legacy applications, or their existing applications.
他们的遗留应用程序或现有的应用程序。
But we will develop new Indian based research
但我们将开展基于印度的新研究。
application that can subscribe to the data from
可以订阅数据的应用程序
the server and then >> I mean,
服务器然后 >> 我的意思是，
decrypt to the data and verify the data and
解密数据并验证数据
then store the data in a database that can be used by the existing application.
然后将数据存储在现有应用程序可以使用的数据库中。
And we will also have an NDN data consumer that
我们还将拥有一个NDN数据消费者，它将
will perform the substance corruption and
将执行实质性的数据损坏和
publication activities and also send and
发表活动以及发送和
receive data, sorry, interest and data packets.
接收数据、抱歉、兴趣和数据包。
So this overall enhanced system will provide the fine
所以这个全面增强的系统将提供精细
grained data access control capability and
精细的数据访问控制能力和
also real-time data distribution capability.
还有实时数据分发能力。
Here's the proposed naming structure for the system.
这是为系统提出的命名结构。
This is strictly directly from the proposal.
这是直接来自提案的内容。
We still need to refine it.
我们仍需要对其进行完善。
So we have the data organization name as
所以我们有数据组织名称作为
the root prefix and then under that we have different studies.
根前缀下面，我们有不同的研究。
And for each study, depending on what kind of data they collect,
对于每项研究，根据它们收集的数据类型，
the each type of data is the branch under that study.
每种数据类型都是该研究下的一个分支。
And then we have more finer grain, data type and user ID.
然后我们有了更精细的数据类型和用户ID。
And then below the user, we have a branch for
然后在用户下面，我们有一个分支用于
the actual data and the encryption key.
实际数据和加密密钥。
We also have branch for access control to encrypt
我们还有一个用于访问控制的加密分支。
the content key and decrypt the content key.
内容密钥和解密内容密钥。
So these are used by the producers and consumers of the data.
所以这些被数据的生产者和消费者所使用。
That's the overall naming scheme and we also have a trust model.
这是整体的命名方案，我们还有一个信任模型。
This is a preliminary model.
这是一个初步模型。
It also needs to be refined.
它还需要进一步完善。
At the top level, we have the overall md2k organizations trust,
在最高层面，我们拥有整个md2k组织的信任，
anchor T which signs each research studies key and
每项研究的关键将由锚点T签署。
each research study is key will sign their data.
每项研究的关键数据将由其签署。
So that's how you authenticate the data produced by
因此，这就是你认证由特定用户产生的特定研究数据的方式。
a particular user from a particular study.
特定研究中的特定用户。
Everything will be traced back to the trust anchor key which is the empty
一切都将追溯到信任锚定密钥，即为空。
two-key organizations key and we have developed a preliminary schemas for
两把组织密钥，我们已经为其开发了一个初步的架构。
validating the keys, and the data.
验证密钥和数据。
And how do we support the real time data distribution and access control?
我们如何支持实时数据分发和访问控制？
We will continue to use the existing
我们将继续使用现有的
NDN libraries and code.
我们将继续使用现有的NDN库和代码。
For the subscription to the data,
为了订阅数据，
we will use the PSync library which has a Pub/Sub API
我们将使用具有发布/订阅 API 的 PSync 库。
to discover and subscribe to data streams.
以发现和订阅数据流。
And then the producers are here is actually just
然后这里的生产者实际上只是
the md2k center after they have collected the data,
在他们收集了数据之后的md2k中心，
they will use the name based access control scheme to protect the data.
他们将使用基于名称的访问控制方案来保护数据。
The data is encrypted based on the access control policies.
数据根据访问控制策略进行了加密。
Here we need to develop a schema to specify these access control policies.
这里我们需要开发一个模式来指定这些访问控制策略。
Here is just an example.
这里只是一个例子。
For example, the users who are allowed to access the data,
例如，被允许访问数据的用户，
here you can specify which data set the user is allowed to access.
在这里，您可以指定用户被允许访问哪些数据集。
And the user is only allowed to access a user's data if
用户只有在以下情况下才被允许访问用户的数据：
the timestamp is between 9 AM and 6 PM, and
时间戳在上午9点至下午6点之间，且
the location is in this person's office, and
位置位于此人的办公室内，且
the permission is to read not to write the data.
权限是读取而不是写入数据。
So we will develop this kind of schema to specify the access control policies and
那么我们将开发这种模式来指定访问控制策略，
then the library will be used to automatically
然后库将被用来自动
generate the keys to site to encrypt and sign the data.
生成密钥以对网站进行加密和数据签名。
And then use the next scheme to distribute
然后使用下一个方案来分发
the key encryption and decryption keys.
加密和解密的关键密钥。
>> Have about another minute.
>> 大概还有一分钟。
>> Okay, so in this past summer, we have developed a next scheme
>> 好的，所以在这个过去的夏天，我们开发了一个新方案
that can enforce policies that have spatial and temporal attributes.
可以实施具有空间和时间属性的策略。
For example, you can specify the time interval and the location of the user and
例如，您可以指定用户的时间间隔和位置，以及
my student launching will present this particular scheme tomorrow.
我的学生将在明天展示这个特定的方案。
This is the last slide.
这是最后一张幻灯片。
The project hasn't started yet.
项目还没有开始。
It will officially start next month.
它将在下个月正式开始。
And when the system is ready,
并且当系统准备好时，
we plan to do a trial deployment over the NDN test bed,
我们计划在NDN测试床上进行一次试验部署，
so that researchers can connect to the test bed and
以便研究人员可以连接到测试床并且
receive the data in real-time.
接收实时数据。
And this, we have a team composed of me and the three students from my group.
而这个，我们有一个由我和我组的三个学生组成的团队。
Santosh Kumar and Nasir Ali who is a research assistant
桑托什·库马尔和研究助理纳西尔·阿里。
professor in my department, and Lixia and two of her students.
我系的教授，以及丽霞和她的两名学生。
The website is at mguarded.md2k.org.
该网站位于 mguarded.md2k.org。
That's for the presentation.
这是用于演示的。
>> Thank you, Lan.
谢谢，蓝。
Are there any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Think we have time for this one?
我们有时间做这个吗？
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
Hey, hear me?
嘿，听见我了吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Hi, this is a Ageque from Canada.
>> 嗨，我是来自加拿大的Ageque。
I want to ask the professor plan one is have
我想问教授计划一是有~!@#$%^&*()
you ever considered combined NDN with
您是否曾经考虑过结合NDN~!@#$%^&*()
the IPMFS all together to do the same thing?
您是否曾经考虑过结合NDN和IPMFS一起来完成同样的事情？我们实际上在内部讨论过这个问题。
>> We actually discussed internally
我们实际上在内部讨论过这个问题。
about IPFS a while back.
所以我认为他们试图做的是NDN想要实现的目标。
So I think they're trying to do what NDN is trying to achieve,
but at a higher level at the application level and being a network layer.
但在更高层次上，在应用层级，同时也是一个网络层。
Being an architecture that starts from the network layer,
作为一种从网络层开始的架构，
I think NDN has some advantages over IPFS.
我认为NDN相比于IPFS有一些优势。
So I think for this project,
所以我认为对于这个项目来说，
we we are not going to try to use IPFS.
我们不打算尝试使用IPFS。
But because NDN already provides the capabilities
但因为NDN已经提供了这些功能，
of what IPFS track is trying to achieve.
IPFS追踪试图实现的目标。
At least for this particular project, we can just directly use NDN.
至少对于这个特定项目，我们可以直接使用NDN。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Yeah, well, it just is the I would stand for file.
>> 是的，它的I应该代表文件。
So therefore I think ipfs handles the file objects
所以我认为IPFS处理的是文件对象。
as opposed to hear more generic data objects.
它与处理更通用的数据对象相反。
It's a kind of design the into the system as opposed
它是一种设计，与系统中的相反。
to running an overlay on top of underlying delivery substrate.
它是在底层交付基础设施之上运行的一个叠加层。
>> Okay, so thank you Lamb, very nice presentation.
好的，非常感谢Lamb，演讲非常精彩。
The last talk of the session is.
这场会议的最后一个报告是。
From Ilya Balding, he is the director for network research and
伊利亚·鲍尔丁发表的，他是网络研究与Renzi基础设施的负责人。
infrastructure at Renzi.
他在Renzi的基础设施方面发挥了领导作用。
He has played a leading leading role in deploying EXA Genie and
他在部署EXA Genie方面发挥了领导性的作用。
then now he is the lead bi for fabric.
他现在是fabric的主要商业智能负责人。
He's going to share with us a talk on fabric scan capabilities and use cases.
他将与我们分享关于fabric扫描功能和使用案例的讲座。
>> Ilya can you share your screen please.
>> 伊利亚，你能分享一下你的屏幕吗？
>> Susmit, I think Ilya is having trouble connecting,
>> 苏斯米特，我觉得伊利亚连接有问题，
okay, replied to his email with the phone number to dial in instead.
好的，我已经回复了他的电子邮件，并提供了电话号码以便他能够电话接入。
I don't know what are you able to do so in time.
我不知道你是否能及时做到这一点。
>> Do you want me to share the slides?
>> 你希望我分享幻灯片吗？
>> If he does dialing.
>> 如果他拨打电话的话。
I gave him the number the blue jeans dialing number.
我给了他蓝色牛仔裤的拨号码。
>> Okay. Just a minute.
好的，稍等一下。
>> Let me get it ready in case he can join, but
如果他能加入的话，我先准备好，不过
if you want to move it to another session, that's fine.
如果你想把它移到另一个会议时段，那也可以。
>> We can probably start the panel and if he shows up,
我们可能会开始小组讨论，如果他出现了，
we give him an opportunity after the panel.
我们可以在小组讨论后给他一个机会。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Thank you Susmit and all the presenters.
>> 谢谢Susmit和所有的演讲者。
Christos, are you ready?
Christos，你准备好了吗？
>> Yes, I am here.
>> 是的，我在这里。
>> All right.
>> 好的。
Thank you, everybody.
谢谢大家。
So we're moving on to the automotive panel and
我们现在转向汽车行业小组讨论。
a pleasure to welcome the three panelists on the automotive panel.
很高兴欢迎三位小组成员加入汽车行业小组讨论。
Mike Westra from Ford, Ted Guild from MIT and W3C and Tao Zhang from NIST,
迈克·韦斯特拉来自福特汽车公司，泰德·吉尔德来自麻省理工学院和万维网联盟，张涛来自美国国家标准与技术研究院，
this is gonna be a slightly different panel, we don't have any slides.
这将是一个略有不同的小组讨论，我们没有任何幻灯片。
And I think that's the right approach for a panel on automotive
我认为这对于汽车行业的小组讨论来说是正确的做法。
networking which seems to be fairly new, very new rather in the Indian community.
网络联络在印度社区似乎是相当新的，甚至可以说是非常新的。
So, we will have about ten minute introductions from each of the panelists
所以，我们将会有大约十分钟的时间让每位小组成员进行介绍。
and then we will devote the time to taking questions from the audience and
接下来我们将用时间来回答观众的提问。
even give you an opportunity for the panelists to ask questions to each other.
甚至还将为小组成员之间互相提问提供机会。
I am very excited about automotive networking.
我对汽车联网感到非常兴奋。
To me, it seems that it's a new frontier in networking.
对我来说，这似乎是联网领域的一个新前沿。
And with this panel, I think it's a great opportunity to hear from people
通过这个讨论小组，我认为这是一个很好的机会去听取那些人的意见。
who are deep into the automotive world industry, data.
深入了解汽车行业世界的数据。
Sharing and standards and so forth and also new types of uses for
共享以及标准等方面，也包括了新的使用类型。
smart and connected vehicles, including remote controlled cars.
智能且互联的车辆，包括遥控汽车。
The automotive networks are unique.
汽车网络是独一无二的。
They do combine pretty much everything that we've done as networking researchers.
它们几乎结合了我们作为网络研究者所做的所有事情。
So there is large data coming out of multiple cameras in cars.
因此，汽车上的多个摄像头产生了大量数据。
And from HD cameras and lighters.
还有来自高清摄像头和激光雷达的数据。
There's real time requirements.
有实时性要求。
Obviously, there's a lot of heterogeneous communication between different
显然，不同的部分之间存在大量异构通信。
components.
组件。
There's aspects of IOT given all the various ECU and
物联网的方面涉及到了所有不同的电子控制单元（ECU）和
other sensors that are in a car.
其他安装在汽车中的传感器。
But it also goes through areas such as cloud computing,
但它也涉及到云计算等领域，
where telematics is being collected.
其中遥测数据正在被收集。
There's edge computing where data has been processed for video x communication.
数据已在边缘计算中被处理，用于视频x通信。
There's a lot of security and privacy issues and of course
在此之上，还有许多安全性和隐私问题，当然……
on top of all of that, the industry has to deal with cars that can be on the road for
在此之上，该行业还必须处理那些可以在路上行驶的汽车，
the next ten twenty years and potentially support these cars and
在接下来的十到二十年内，甚至可能支持这些汽车并且
keep them up to date for the safety and cyber security and so forth.
保持它们在安全性和网络安全等方面的更新。
So, pretty tall order for the automotive industry in this regard.
因此，在这方面，汽车行业面临着相当艰巨的任务。
The other challenge comes from telematics or the data that comes from cars.
另一个挑战来自于远程信息处理技术，或者说是来自汽车的数据。
We've heard the expression there are sensors on wheels.
我们已经听说过这样的表达：车轮上有传感器。
And all these data has great potential to benefit the drivers in terms of
这些数据都有极大的潜力在以下方面惠及驾驶员：
maintenance, in terms of safety.
在监控车辆是否遭受入侵以及维护方面，在安全方面。
In terms of monitoring vehicles for intrusions and
providing cybersecurity, but also other users such as the insurance company,
在提供网络安全的同时，还有其他用户，例如保险公司，
who would love to have these data to create better insurance models and
希望利用这些数据来创建更好的保险模型，并且希望通过降低利率来帮助我们其他人。
hopefully help the rest of us with reduced interest rates.
希望通过降低利率来帮助我们其他人。
The data can also benefit society.
数据也能惠及社会。
We've seen cases with connected cars,
我们已经看到了具有互联功能的汽车的案例，
where the cars in front of you alert the cars behind them for
在这种情况下，前方的车辆会提醒后方的车辆注意
hazards and making the road safer for everybody else.
隐私、数据所有权以及使道路对所有人更安全的风险。
But of course with all the data come big issues in privacy, data ownership and
但当然，随着所有这些数据的涌现，也带来了隐私、数据所有权等重大问题，以及
so forth.
等等。
And finally as we're moving into level four, level five autonomous vehicles, and
最后，随着我们进入四级、五级自动驾驶汽车领域，
as we are working on societal acceptance and driver acceptance and so forth,
在我们努力获得社会接受和驾驶员接受等方面的同时，
there's issues that we can explore on the way there.
在我们前进的过程中，有一些问题我们可以探索。
For example, Tao was working on remotely controlled vehicles,
例如，陶正在研究远程控制车辆，
which, could be thought as an inter in STEM to autonomous vehicles.
它也可以被认为是STEM领域自主车辆的一个介入点。
But it could also be thought, as a model, by itself.
但它也可以被认为是一个单独的模型。
Looking at the future of smart vehicles.
展望智能汽车的未来。
So, with that, hopefully brief introduction, I will let our panelists
那么，在这简短的介绍之后，我将让我们的小组成员
give us a brief introduction of themselves and talk about these
介绍一下他们自己，并讨论这些
the issues that their industry and organizations are concerned about.
他们所在行业和组织关心的问题。
And then we will move on to discussion the sequence will be
接下来我们将继续讨论，顺序将是
I will have Mike Westra from Ford first, followed by Ted Guild.
首先是福特公司的Mike Westra，其次是Ted Guild。
And then finally, Tao from NIST.
然后最后是来自NIST的Tao。
So Mike, if you're ready please go ahead and
那么迈克，如果你准备好了，请开始吧。
unmute and give us your perspective.
取消静音并给我们分享你的观点。
>> Okay. Great, thank you, can you hear me?
>> 好的。太好了，谢谢，你能听见我说话吗？
>> Yeah.
>> 是的。
>> [COUGH] You can.
>> [咳嗽] 你可以的。
I'm Mike Westra.
我是迈克·韦斯特拉。
I'm the manager of connected product cyber security at Ford Motor Company
我是福特汽车公司联网产品网络安全的经理。
and, to just want to thank everybody on the panel for being here today.
同时，我想感谢今天在座的各位小组成员。
And so Christos asked to kind of highlight really quickly in just a minute or two,
克里斯托斯要求我们在一两分钟内简要突出一下，
some of the challenges that automakers are facing around data at the moment.
一些汽车制造商目前在数据方面面临的挑战。
And so he highlighted especially
他特别强调了
the data that's being collected into the back end and
正在后端收集的数据以及
it's kind of a confluence of cyber security and
它是网络安全和
government policy in some ways ironically at the at the moment.
政府政策在某种程度上当前反而具有讽刺意味。
So Europe.
所以，欧洲。
Is kinda working through a lot of the challenges right now, and
正在努力克服许多挑战。
there's a couple of models that they've explored from.
他们已经探索了几种模型。
So their end goal is to provide sort of an open ecosystem,
所以他们的最终目标是提供一种开放的生态系统，
where the data can be shared among interested
在这个生态系统中，数据可以在感兴趣的参与方之间共享。
parties based on the model that you're looking at.
在你所观察的模型中，数据可以在各方之间基于该模型共享。
It's kinda along a continuum from the OEMs, or
这在一定程度上是一个连续体，从原始设备制造商（OEMs）开始，或者说……
kinda intended to be the stewards of the data with an extended sorta vehicle.
有点像是数据的管理者，用一种扩展型的车辆。
And this can be data from what had historically been
以及这可能是来自历史上一直存在的数据，
repair data all the way to geolocation data, driving behavior data.
修复数据一直到地理位置数据、驾驶行为数据。
So there's obviously a lot of PII concerns.
所以显然存在很多个人身份信息（PII）相关的担忧。
So from one end to the extreme where the automakers are kinda the stewards,
所以从一个极端，汽车制造商在某种程度上是数据的管理者，
Europe seems to be advocating a neutral server sort of approach,
欧洲似乎在提倡采用一种中立服务器的方法，
where there's a neutral server that is kinda where the data gets collected.
在那里有一个中立服务器，数据就是在那里被收集的。
To requirements that the vehicle directly
满足要求车辆需要直接
connect to any third party, theoretically,
连接到任何第三方，理论上，
the user has authorized to collect that data.
用户已授权收集那些数据。
To even some models that some of the aftermarket folks are advocating, where it
甚至包括一些售后服务人员所推崇的某些型号，其中它……
mandates that their code actually execute inside of the safety vehicle environment,
要求他们的代码实际上要在安全车辆环境内执行，
which automakers have a great deal of sort of heartburn over.
这让许多汽车制造商感到非常头疼。
I'll focus mostly on kinda the side, and
我将主要关注一边，以及
some of the challenges really are data collection is not free.
一些挑战确实是数据收集并不是免费的。
And so a lot of the expectation,
所以很多的期望，
unfortunately from some of the aftermarket folks has been, well,
不幸的是，来自一些售后市场的人的期望是，嗯，
we'll make you guys collect the data and then and then give it to us.
我们会让你们收集数据，然后再把它交给我们。
And that's kinda unfortunately the approach that's occurring in some
这种做法不幸地正在一些地方发生。
places in the US as the policy battle is being fought.
这场政策之战正在美国的一些地方进行着。
It's supposed extension of right to repair.
这是对维修权的一种预期扩展。
The challenges is less, the normal IT kinds of
挑战较小，更多的是常规IT类型的。
mechanisms to share the data with PKI and TLS,
数据共享机制采用PKI和TLS，
and some of that, is fairly well adapted.
一些已经相当适应了。
The bigger challenge is around a lot of the policy aspects.
这更大的挑战在于很多政策层面的问题。
And so there's a lot of hand waving on, well, who's gonna authorize that
因此，关于谁将对此进行授权，存在很多不明确和随意的做法。
customers and entities are really truly who they say they are?
客户和实体是否真的是他们所声称的那个人？
And that's really the cracks of the problem.
这确实是问题的关键所在。
It's less the technical aspects,
这更少是技术层面的问题，
and it's really boils down to much more of a policy kinda concern.
这实际上更多地归结为一种政策层面的担忧。
Where, historically, the OEM is kinda the steward of the data,
在历史上，OEM通常是数据的管理者，
steward of the customer.
客户的管家。
Folks are trying to challenge that, and then there's not
人们正在尝试挑战这一点，然后就没有了。
sorta the corresponding understanding of, well, how do I know that this person
有点像是相应的理解，那么，我怎么知道这个人
that is demanding data from a particular vehicle is in fact the customer?
是否确实是要求特定车辆数据的客户？
Or is truly a valid aftermarket,
或者确实是一个合法的售后市场，
entity that should actually have access to the data?
实体是否确实应该有权访问这些数据？
One of the things that we fortunately do see when we look at the data for
我们幸运地看到，在我们查看数据时，
right to repair data, we see a lot of data that comes in from
我们看到很多来自修理权数据的信息，
places in China and Eastern Europe.
来自中国和东欧的地方。
And the data isn't sort of as sensitive today, but
但是数据今天并不是那么敏感，不过
there's certainly a large concern just handing over sensitive PII data
肯定有很大的担忧，只是随意地交出敏感的个人身份信息(PII)数据。
to entities that haven't been properly sorta authenticated.
向那些尚未得到适当认证的实体交出。
And truly capturing customer consent, that they really want that data exchanged.
并且确实捕捉到客户的同意，他们确实希望交换那些数据。
And so a lot of those policy areas are really underdeveloped or
很多这样的政策领域实际上还不够成熟或者
not really robustly defined.
还没有被严格明确定义。
As well as just the business aspects of, well, who's paying to collect that data?
以及，嗯，谁来支付收集那些数据的费用这样的商业方面的问题？
Because cellular data is not free nor necessarily cheap in mass.
因为蜂窝数据并不是免费的，而且在大量使用时也不一定便宜。
And so there's a lot of challenges that will need to get sorted out probably over
所以在接下来的几年里，有很多挑战需要解决，以弄清楚这一切将如何运作。
the next couple of years as to how that how that's all going to work.
在接下来的几年里，我们需要弄清楚这一切将如何运作。
And so it's less on the vehicle side, but
而且它更少涉及车辆方面，但是
it's a lot more on how is the data gonna be managed.
它更多的是关于数据将如何被管理。
So that's what I've got to share.
所以这就是我要分享的内容。
So Chris, if you want to hand it off to the next person.
那么Chris，如果你想把它交给下一个人。
>> Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，Mike。
Thank you. Thank you for
谢谢。谢谢你。
highlighting all these important issues with data.
强调所有这些重要的数据问题。
So Ted, we'll let you come in.
所以泰德，我们会让你进来。
And I'm sure you have a few things to say about data.
我相信你对数据肯定有一些想法要说。
So go ahead.
那就请继续。
>> Sure, my name is Ted Guild.
当然，我的名字是Ted Guild。
I'm a researcher at MIT where I've been the last 20 years.
我是麻省理工学院的一名研究员，过去20年我一直在那里工作。
A good chunk of that has been, well, all that's been working for the W3C.
在这其中的很大一部分时间，嗯，全部都是在为万维网联盟（W3C）工作。
Good chunk, that is the head of IT organization where we also did,
在这其中很大一部分，也就是我们还参与了IT组织的领导工作，
not just the infrastructure for the organization and defenses for
不仅仅是为了组织的基础设施和防御，还有
ourselves, but working on sort of new web security sort of prototypes.
我们自己，但也在研究某种新的网络安全原型。
Try to sorta lead by example kinda thing.
尝试通过身体力行来起到示范作用。
Currently, I am the lead of the WC automotive activity,
目前，我是WC汽车活动的负责人，
which I'll describe in brief.
我将简要描述一下。
I'm also the stock contact for the geospatial on the web activity.
我还是网络地理空间活动的股票联络人。
And I also do some secondary research on
我还做一些次级研究。
connective vehicles and [INAUDIBLE].
连接车辆和[不可辨识]。
So in brief, the [INAUDIBLE] vehicle ecosystem.
所以简而言之，[不可辨识]车辆生态系统。
It's also possible to run this on data that's already been off boarded and
它也可以在已经下线的数据上运行。
resides in the cloud.
驻留在云端。
We're using a common data model.
我们正在使用一个通用数据模型。
Every auto manufacturer currently does data differently,
每个汽车制造商目前都以不同的方式处理数据，
which makes trying to normalize and use that more difficult.
这使得尝试对这些数据进行标准化和使用变得更加困难。
And I'm enjoying a Mike Westra's photo problem in the background.
我在背景中欣赏着Mike Westra的摄影作品。
Better someone's messing with him real time.
总比有人实时捣乱要好。
Always be careful of security conferences, even remote ones.
始终要注意安全会议，即使是远程的。
So come in data model, we're joined in collaboration Genivi.
所以在数据模型中，我们加入了与Genivi的合作。
We're using web technologies because the various people that are.
我们使用网络技术是因为有各种各样的人在使用。
OEMs, something they've watched it in the vehicle now established partnerships,
OEM们，他们已经在车辆中观察到了这一点，现在建立了合作伙伴关系，
some they may be coerced to in time.
有些可能会随着时间被迫接受。
These guys are not the Automotive Engineers.
这些人不是汽车工程师。
But most of them should be familiar with web technologies since
但他们中的大多数应该熟悉网络技术，因为
that's the most dominant platform on the planet on the planet.
这是地球上最主导的平台。
We're bringing to the cloud.
我们正在将其引入云端。
We have an ontology that we build on top of this common data model, the SSO,
我们在这个通用数据模型之上构建了一个本体，即SSO，
which enables artificial intelligence machine learning, various analytics and
使得人工智能机器学习、各种分析等成为可能，
enables WC's web of things, which is an abstraction layer on top of IoT,
使得WC的物联网之网成为可能，它是建立在物联网之上的一个抽象层，
which is fragmented as badly if not worse than automotive.
它的碎片化程度严重，甚至可能比汽车行业还要糟糕。
Ask for help sorta abstract out normalize things and you can define a car as
请求帮助，抽象出来，规范化事物，你可以将一辆车定义为
a thing on the WC's web of things, decide what capabilities you want to expose.
在万维网的物联网上的一个东西，决定你想要暴露哪些功能。
There's also sort of a whole laundry list of things that this sorta opens up.
这也某种程度上打开了一整套事物清单的大门。
As far as these technologies, there's definitely a need for it and
在这些技术方面，它们无疑是有需求的，并且
via best practices, things that can help other manufacturers feel comfortable,
通过最佳实践，那些能够帮助其他制造商感到舒适的事物，
laying people in as far as this periodic reviews, what they're allowed to awkward,
进行定期审查，以及他们被允许的尴尬情况，
that sort of a resources making sure that in bandwidth is being paid for
确保带宽费用得到支付的那种资源。
in a reasonable and ideally non-discriminatory turns.
在合理且理想情况下不歧视的轮次中。
Various things like that.
各种各样的事情。
We're also have a few things on the back burner as far as going forward.
我们还有一些事情在酝酿中，以便将来推进。
I try to stay on the technical solutions and
我尽量专注于技术解决方案和
avoid the political topics in the space.
避免在这个领域涉及政治话题。
But of course, I have my own views,
但当然了，我有我自己的看法，
I think that there is a possibility to have a medium and
我认为有可能存在一个中介和
safe environment between OEMs, these third parties are clamoring for data.
在OEMs之间创造一个安全的环境，这些第三方正争相索要数据。
And I agree that is if OEMs are incurring costs and
我同意，如果OEMs在承担成本并且
>> Very good.
很好。
Thank you, Ted.
谢谢你，泰德。
[COUGH] All right, so Tao, please go ahead,
好的，那么请你开始吧，陶。
introduce yourself and tell us a little bit about what you do.
介绍一下你自己，告诉我们一些关于你工作的事情。
>> Okay, hi everyone, this is Tao Zhang from NIST.
好的，大家好，我是来自国家标准技术研究院的张涛。
I joined NIST last year, just about a year ago.
我去年加入了国家标准技术研究院，大约就是一年前。
I manage the Emerging Network Technologies Group at NIST.
我在国家标准技术研究院管理新兴网络技术组。
So before joining NIST, I was in the private sector, doing research and
所以在加入国家标准技术研究院之前，我在私营部门从事研究和产品开发，以及企业战略。
product development, and corporate strategy.
产品开发和企业战略。
I was with Cisco Systems for about six weeks, I was the CTO chief scientist for
我在思科系统公司工作了大约六周，我是首席技术官兼首席科学家。
Cisco's smart connected vehicles business.
思科的智能互联汽车业务。
Helped actually build that business, and I was a chief scientist,
帮助实际构建了那个业务，我曾是首席科学家，
and director of research groups in Bellcore/Telcordia.
和贝尔核心/泰尔科迪亚研究小组的负责人。
So which is part of the system over the data focus of
所以哪一部分是系统中专注于数据的部分？
work has been vehicle to networking andwireless.
工作已经转向了网络和无线通信。
So today, really a great pleasure to be here to share with everyone
今天能在这里和大家分享，真是非常高兴。
some thoughts as I'd like to mention maybe two areas.
我想提到两个方面的一些想法。
One of them, so we all know as Ted and Mike mentioned already,
其中一个，正如Ted和Mike已经提到的，
data generated by the cars is an tremendous new issue.
汽车产生的数据是一个巨大的新问题。
And we all know there's a ton of data being generated on an hourly basis,
我们都知道，每小时都会产生大量的数据，
those are the data we need to train our machine learning models to do things,
这些数据是我们需要用来训练我们的机器学习模型去做事情的。
to monitor the car, to control the car, and to protect a car.
为了监控汽车、控制汽车以及保护汽车。
So currently, what we do is that we send all this data to the cloud.
所以目前我们所做的就是将所有这些数据发送到云端。
And we train machine learning models over there and
然后我们在那里训练机器学习模型，
that was sent the models back to the cars to use.
并将这些模型发送回汽车中使用。
And sending those data to the cloud is getting more and more invisible.
并且将这些数据发送到云端变得越来越不显眼。
So then the question is, did we explore other other capabilities?
那么问题就是，我们是否探索了其他的能力？
For example, agile learning.
例如，敏捷学习。
Can we have those cars to learn locally?
我们能否让这些车在本地学习？
But of course, the cars are limited in process and powers,
但当然，这些车在处理能力和动力方面都有限制，
they're limited in data, even though they have a lot,
它们在数据方面受限，即便它们拥有很多数据，
but they don't have to global view of it, everything.
但它们并没有对所有事物的全局视角。
And the question is what can those cars learn?
那么问题是，这些汽车能学到什么？
And how can they share the knowledge they learned from their local data
那么它们如何共享它们从本地数据中学到的知识呢？
with the cloud?
与云端？
So the cloud rather than collecting raw data from every cars,
所以云端不是从每辆车收集原始数据，
can be collecting knowledge learned by the cars and transferred to the cloud.
而是收集车辆学到的知识，并将其传输到云端。
And then they can leverage those to build better and more powerful models.
然后他们可以利用这些知识建立更好、更强大的模型。
So the knowledge learn, for example, in terms of machine learning models,
所获得的知识，例如在机器学习模型方面，
parameters and so on, and it will be much,
参数等等，它将会更小，
much smaller than the size of the raw data.
比原始数据的大小要小得多。
And so
因此
that's one of the areas I think maybe worth while looking into in the future.
这是我认为将来值得研究的领域之一。
Another area is over the past several yeas, two, three years I will say,
另一个领域是，在过去的几年里，我会说，大概两三年来，
and there is an increasing amount of effort in the industry and
在这个行业里，越来越多的努力正在被投入到……
developing not just self driving cars but remote controlled cars.
发展不仅仅是自动驾驶汽车，还包括遥控汽车。
So remote driving are tiny operation.
因此，远程驾驶是微小的操作。
So today for example, that effort has been focused mostly on use and
因此，今天为例，这种努力主要集中在使用上。
human remote drivers to help autonomous cars to handle tougher tricky
人类远程驾驶员帮助自动驾驶汽车处理更棘手的难题。
cases that the cars themselves do not have enough intelligence to handle yet.
这些情况是汽车自身的智能还不足以处理的。
And there happens to be quite a lot still.
而且那里确实还有很多。
And they are already a lot of interesting issues over there,
而且那里已经有很多有趣的问题了，
trying to overcome.
试图克服。
But for researchers,
但对于研究人员来说，
actually you can see bigger potentials along that direction.
实际上，沿着那个方向你可以看到更大的潜力。
So we don't have to stop at human teleoperators
所以我们不必仅限于人类遥控操作员。
as the network's become better well as we move into 5G.
随着网络变得更好，以及我们进入5G时代。
As the AI capabilities become more advanced, you could envision that one day,
随着人工智能能力变得更加先进，你可以想象有一天，
it could become possible that the technologies will allow us to
甚至可能会有技术让我们能够
even offload some of the driving intelligence away from the cars.
甚至可能将部分驾驶智能从汽车中转移出去。
And to the edge systems to the cloud systems.
并且向边缘系统以及云系统转移。
And so you'll see and as sort of an interesting
所以你会看到这是一种有趣的
framework that allows you to distribute and
架构，它允许你分布和
driving intelligence along that continuum between the vehicle and the cloud.
驾驶智能在车辆和云端之间的连续体上发挥作用。
And so with the two extremes being who is the white straight away extreme being all
而两个极端的情况是，谁是白色直线的极端。
the intelligence and being placed on the car that is what we have today.
这种智能被安置在我们今天所拥有的汽车上。
And so the question then becomes, and will that be visible,
那么问题就变成了，这将会是可见的吗？
how would that be visible, what it depends on?
这将如何可见，它依赖于什么？
And what would you be challenges for example,
例如，你会遇到哪些挑战？
people will immediately point out, hey, what about the network?
人们会立刻指出，嘿，网络怎么样了？
What happens if the natural delays get bad and so on?
如果自然延迟变得很糟糕会怎么样呢？
So there are challenges.
所以存在着挑战。
And so that is another area that I think maybe it was loud looking into.
所以那是另一个我认为可能值得深入研究的领域。
So I'll stop there, thank you >> Thank you, Tao, thank you very much.
所以我就讲到这里，谢谢 >> 谢谢，涛，非常感谢你。
So those were the presentations from our presenters and
那些就是我们演讲者的报告内容。
I do encourage the audience to ask questions as as they come along.
我鼓励观众随时提问。
I wanted to start by sort of addressing what the Tao said and ask Mike.
我想首先讲一下道的教义，并问问迈克。
So Mike, I'll put on a very compelling view for
那么迈克，我将提出一个非常引人注目的观点来讨论
what the future of smart and connected vehicles might look like.
未来智能和互联车辆可能会是什么样子。
Is this something that the automakers are looking at?
这是汽车制造商正在考虑的事情吗？
Can you tell us a little bit about how Ford and in general, the automakers,
您能不能跟我们简单谈谈福特，以及一般的汽车制造商，
are looking at the future of autonomous vehicles?
正在探讨自动驾驶汽车的未来吗？
Is this still l four, l five, or are we looking at interim solutions or
这还是四级、五级自动驾驶吗，还是我们正在寻找过渡性的解决方案，或者……
ten alternatives?
十种替代方案？
>> I think you'll see this is the state of the art advanced for
>> 我认为你会看到这是先进的艺术状态
long to two kind of pipelines.
长达两种类型的管道。
One's sort of what really is kind of advanced and
一种是真的相当先进的类型。
those will start to bleed into like level two.
这些将开始渗透进入类似于二级的层面。
And they'll have more and more connectivity, and
它们将拥有越来越多的连通性，
they'll allow more to be done kind of with the with the operator,
它们将允许操作者完成更多的工作，
sort of ultimately in control.
最终在某种程度上掌控。
And you'll start to see more sort of vision systems, radar, and
你将会开始看到更多的视觉系统、雷达等设备，
more sensors sort of supporting that beyond even what Tesla is doing today.
更多的传感器将支持这一点，甚至超出了特斯拉今天所做的。
And then the autonomous vehicles will kind of work from the top down,
然后，自动驾驶汽车将从上到下开始工作，
where pretty much the state of the art now is sort of
目前的最先进技术大体上可以说是这样的。
safety operator driven level 4 autonomous vehicles.
安全操作员驾驶的4级自动驾驶汽车。
And they have probably a couple of 100,000$ in sensors
而且他们可能在传感器上投入了几十万美元。
that will all become much cheaper over time.
随着时间的推移，这些都将变得便宜得多。
I think a lot of people see those as being more fleet centric,
我认为很多人将这些视为更加以车队为中心。
at least for the short and medium term.
至少在短期和中期内。
You read the press where a lot of that investment is, is being driven
你读到了新闻报道，很多投资正是由此推动的。
by the likes of Google and Uber, along with the traditional automakers.
由谷歌和优步以及传统汽车制造商等公司推动。
And so you'll see a lot of that kind of driven lower and lower.
所以你会看到很多这种东西被越来越多地压低。
But the reality is a lot of that where the intent there is to get rid of
但现实是很多这样的情况，其目的是要摆脱它。
the steering wheel and provide sort of service.
的方向盘并提供某种服务。
That requires a whole different level of safety and
那需要一种完全不同层次的安全性和
compute and sensors, sort of completely different than Edaf.
计算和传感器，在某种程度上完全不同于Edaf。
Where Edaf can kind of just say, you know what it's raining,
Edaf可以有点就是说，你知道，它在下雨，
I don't know how to deal with this current situation,
我不知道如何应对当前的情况，
I'm gonna make the operator sort of deal with it.
我会让操作员来处理这件事。
level 4 has to be fully autonomous within a geo fenced area and
四级自动驾驶必须在地理围栏限定区域内完全自主。
level 5 is in theory anywhere in the country.
五级自动驾驶理论上可以在国内任何地方运行。
It could fully operate autonomously and
它可以完全自主地运行。
I think even the most aggressive sort of futurists say level 5
我认为即使是最激进的未来主义者也说到5级自动驾驶还有很长的路要走。
is quite a ways out where level 4 is where everybody's trying to shoot
在哪里4级自动驾驶是每个人都在努力尝试达到的目标。
first a sweet spot in terms of how much is going to be onboard versus off board.
首先要找到一个甜蜜点，来确定车载系统与非车载系统之间的平衡。
I think, I don't think we're necessarily unique.
我认为，我们不一定是独一无二的。
In the sort of approach, I think from a safety standpoint, and
在这种方法中，我认为从安全的角度来看，
this is even less cybersecurity, the final decisions as to sort of braking, steering,
这甚至与网络安全关系更小，最终的决定比如制动、转向，
all of the safety operations are done sort of locally on the edge.
所有的安全操作都是在边缘进行的。
And where the cloud comes in, is it will help with the learning,
而云计算的作用在于，它将帮助进行学习，
the process that the tons of processing that's needed for maps and
处理大量所需的地图和导航数据的过程。
for helping around sort of exception.
帮助处理各种异常情况。
So the autonomous vehicle
遇到了一些它没有预料到的情况，例如某种异常。
encounters something it's not,it's sort of anticipating, such as a sort
of construction zone that wasn't previously known.
可能会突然停下来，因为它遇到了之前不知道的施工区域。
It may stop alert, the back end and
可能会突然停下来，然后后端需要一些操作员的支持。
then have to have the back end with some operators support.
然后需要后端得到一些操作员的支持。
Add that to the to the mapping on the fly.
将其即时添加到映射中。
That in routing types of sort of macro routing types of things would
这在路由类型中，类似宏观路由类型的事务中会。
could be happening on the back end the local decision.
可能会在后端发生本地决策。
In terms of this object will almost certainly be done on the edge
在这方面，这个对象几乎肯定会在边缘完成。
just because of safety concerns.
仅仅是因为安全考虑。
>> Great.
太好了。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
Before I let you off the hook, Mike I, wanted to, so well, let me do this first.
在我放你离开之前，迈克，我想，那么，首先让我来做这个。
First of all, let me see if the other two panelists have any.
首先，让我看看其他两位小组成员是否有任何意见。
Follow one on what Mike said though Tao or Ted?
跟随Mike所说的，不过是Tao还是Ted呢？
>> A little bit so I agree with Mike that.
我有点同意Mike的看法。
As far as decisions things need to be done on the edge on the vehicle itself
在决策方面，需要在车辆本身的边缘进行操作。
directly.
你没有时间等待发送某物并直接得到回转。
You don't have the time for the turnarounds at the send something off and
hope for a decision.
但希望能早点得到决定。
But to tell us point sort of earlier insert combining with Mike's.
但要提前告诉我们这一点，某种程度上需要与迈克的内容结合起来。
I do want that information to be off boarded as well and sort of feed.
我也希望那些信息能够被顺利转移并得到传播。
Right now we're seeing quite
目前我们正在见证相当多的
a bit of competition sort of a race towards autonomous vehicles and
一点竞争，有点像是向自动驾驶汽车发展的竞赛。
automated pastures are traditionally both collaborative and competitive.
自动化牧场传统上既是合作性的，也是具有竞争性的。
Limit how and where they collaborate.
限制他们合作的方式和范围。
I think we'll see some partnerships start emerge, more partnerships start emerged
我认为我们将会看到一些合作伙伴关系开始出现，更多的合作伙伴关系将会形成。
around autonomous vehicles that some of them feel there may be falling behind.
围绕自动驾驶汽车，他们中的一些人感觉可能会落后。
And I see them start to get into federated learning and
他们开始涉足联邦学习，
be able to use the data available on both are multiple fleets
能够利用多个车队上可用的数据。
from different auto manufacturers and be able to feed those in and learn from them.
来自不同汽车制造商的传感器变化，并能够吸收这些信息并从中学习。
Because the variation of sensors and
由于传感器的变化以及
these mechanics of the vehicles together will help to create a better understanding
这些车辆的机械原理结合在一起将有助于更好地理解
of the physical world that these objects are moving.
这些物体运动的物理世界。
I think I'll just, he wants to say something as well.
我想我会这样做，他也想说点什么。
Go ahead. Sorry.
继续吧。对不起。
>> No, I'm good.
不，我很好。
No, no, I was done.
不，不，我已经完成了。
Off to you, sir.
给您了，先生。
[BLANK_AUDO] >> Yeah,
[空白音频] >> 是的，
so I view this collective learning between for
所以我认为这是一种集体学习，适用于
example and a vehicle and in the cloud.
例子中的车辆和云端。
Sort of as the next step, we do a lot of pre processing of data on the vehicle,
在下一步中，我们会在车辆上进行大量的数据预处理，
right?
我们试图过滤掉我们认为对某些应用程序不有用的东西。
We try to filter out things we think, are not useful for certain applications.
And we don't send everything generated by the vehicle to the cloud or
我们也不会将车辆生成的所有数据发送到云端，或者
IT, but this sort of collective collaborative learning.
但是这种集体的协作学习。
Between those two entities one and the cloud and
在这两个实体之间，一个是云，
a car sort of represent a next step, right now, rather than sort of a selectively
一辆车在某种程度上代表了下一个阶段，现在，与其说是选择性地
transform, transporting data back and forth, we actually move to one step up.
我们实际上已经向前迈进了一步，不仅仅是来回传输数据。
We actually build knowledge and we started to select which knowledge will learn to
我们实际上在构建知识，并开始选择哪些知识将要学习。
share with other people and how do you share and sharing knowledge actually.
分享给其他人，以及如何分享，实际上分享知识。
Turns out to be and the more complicated matter.
结果证明是一个更为复杂的问题。
And then sharing all that has that opens up a lot of interesting research
然后分享所有这些内容，这为许多有趣的研究打开了大门。
questions for the researchers on this call.
对于在此通话中的研究人员的问题。
So that's where I think it's important and it and
所以我认为这就是它的重要之处。
also this distributed sort of learning.
同时也是这种分布式的学习方式。
And goes beyond what the traditional does do.
并且超越了传统所做的。
As you know today, distributed learning has been going on for quite some time.
如您所知，分布式学习已经进行了相当长的一段时间。
But they tend to focus on distributed learning in a cloud setup.
但他们往往专注于云环境中的分布式学习。
So which is very,
所以这与协作边缘学习和云学习截然不同。
very different from the collaborative edge learning and cloud learning.
与协作边缘学习和云学习截然不同。
In the cloud, for example,
在云端，例如，
you will have data that's accessible by all the distributee knows.
你将拥有所有分发者都能访问的数据。
Right.
对。
And it's the same day and they did it.
而且是同一天，他们做到了。
Yeah. The computers and
是的。电脑和
the cloud nodes are not that limited by processing power.
云节点在处理能力上没有那么受限。
They're much secure and much more secure than for example, the edge nodes.
它们比如边缘节点要安全得多。
And so you can have different ways to handle robustness and
因此，你可以有不同的方法来处理鲁棒性问题。
trustworthiness of the models.
模型的可信赖性。
And when you have sort of cars helping you learn, and all of those
当你有类似于汽车辅助你学习的情况时，以及所有那些情况下，
fundamental assumptions change and most of them don't hold true anymore.
基本假设发生了变化，而且它们中的大多数不再成立。
That impacts the way you develop methods and methods for learning so
这影响了你制定学习方法和学习手段的方式。
and in the future, not even very far future.
所以，在不久的将来，这可能成为一种必要。
So, those learning at edge may become a necessity just
所以，边缘学习可能会成为一种必要。
because the sheer amount of data you're generating and
因为你正在生成的数据量实在是太大了，所以你可能不想也不需要将它们全部发送到云端。
you can or you don't want to send them all into the cloud so
你可能不想也不需要将它们全部发送到云端。
they just sort of want to add to that.
他们只是想要在那基础上增加一些内容。
>> Very good.
>> 非常好。
Thank you Tao.
谢谢涛。
Another question for all three of you right now.
另一个问题给你们三个人。
So we're seeing sort of a convergence between internet technologies and
所以我们正在见证互联网技术与
automotive communication systems and part of it has been facilitated by the move.
汽车通信系统的融合，部分原因是由这一转变所促进的。
Or the apparent adoption of automotive Ethernet
或者是汽车以太网的明显采用。
by the automotive industry, which, with automotive Ethernet,
正在被汽车行业采用，这一行业通过汽车以太网，
we're now looking at much higher speeds, much bigger packets.
我们现在看到的是更高的速度，更大的数据包。
An environment where the internet folks now feel
互联网人现在感觉到的环境
more comfortable in terms of bringing in technologies that they've developed for
在引入他们开发的技术方面感觉更加舒适，
the internet such as security encryption, authentication and so forth.
互联网方面的安全加密、认证等技术。
Our audience is mostly internet researchers.
我们的受众主要是互联网研究人员。
So what would you like to see from internet researchers
那么，您希望从互联网研究人员那里看到什么？
in terms of contributing or collaborating with the automotive sector?
在汽车行业方面的贡献或合作上？
Are there other good opportunities?
汽车行业还有其他好的机会吗？
Are there obvious things that the automotive sector
汽车行业有没有明显的事情？
can collaborate with internet researchers?
可以与互联网研究人员合作吗？
>> Sure, I'll take the first swing at it.
>> 当然，我会先来尝试一下。
I think yeah, I mean,
我认为是的，我的意思是，
it's very true that sort of Ethernet is becoming kind of a, I think well.
这是非常正确的，以太网正在变得有点像是，我认为嗯。
V the default high speed link and things like flex Ray and
大多数可能会很快被它所取代。
most will probably be eclipsed by it fairly quickly
that some automakers had used for high speed links.
有些汽车制造商曾用于高速链接的。
That doesn't mean that is necessarily going away anytime soon for real time and
这并不意味着它会很快就真的消失，对于实时和
other uses I had, our sort
我曾经有的其他用途，我们这种方式的主要网络专家有点这样描述它。
of lead network expert kinda described it this way.
主要网络专家有点这样描述它。
Unlike a somebody who's setting up sort of an IT network on an enterprise,
与那些在企业中设置某种IT网络的人不同，
where they have to, basically make sure that the network is set up.
他们必须确保网络已经建立起来。
You've got dozens, in hundreds, or thousands of clients.
你有几十个、几百个，甚至上千个客户。
It's kind of the opposite in a vehicle.
在车辆中情况却恰恰相反。
You need determinism, reliability,
你需要确定性和可靠性，
and you're building the same relatively small network with maybe.
你正在构建一个相对较小的网络，可能会有。
Anywhere from four to a couple of dozen nodes on it, but
你在构建的这个网络上可能有四个到几十个节点，但是
you're building that same network a million different times.
你正在将同一个网络构建一百万次。
And it's in your basically replicating it nearly identically,
你基本上是在几乎完全相同地复制它，
sort of a million times as you're building vehicles, and
你在制造车辆时，需要确保那个网络能够可靠地工作，并且要仿佛你已经复制了它上百万次一样。
you need to make sure that that network behaves reliably and
你需要确保那个网络行为可靠，
sort of operates consistently.
它在某种程度上能够持续稳定地运作。
And then just from a sort of a technology standpoint,
从技术角度来看，
I think on the wire, you're gonna see a number of similarities.
我认为在传输层面上，你会发现有许多相似之处。
So you'll still have TCP/IP and UDP.
所以你仍然会使用TCP/IP和UDP。
On the wire, the physical wiring will be different just because of some of the,
在物理层面上，由于一些原因，物理布线将会有所不同，
>> [COUGH]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Unique physical properties in
>> 独特的物理特性在
the vehicle, and some of the cost constraints and
车辆以及一些成本限制和
you may see a few additional things on the network,
您可能会在网络上看到一些额外的东西，
such as sort of time synchronization for media and some other types of things.
例如某种类型的媒体时间同步以及其他一些类型的事物。
And you may see statically defined networks that go back
您可能会看到一些静态定义的网络，它们可以追溯到过去。
to making sure that everything is consistent and whatnot.
以确保一切都是一致的等等。
But at the same time, from a security standpoint.
但同时，从安全的角度来看。
There's a lot of excitement, hey, can I use VLANs?
有很多人感到兴奋，我可以使用VLAN吗？
Can I start to do things that add various sort of switching and
我可以开始做添加各种交换功能的事情吗？
firewall layers to just sort of isolate and shape traffic for
防火墙层来隔离和塑造流量以便进行
that things are isolated and segregated appropriately to keep domains separate.
事物被适当地隔离和分隔，以保持各个域的独立性。
So, I think it's similar.
所以，我认为它们是相似的。
You'll see a lot of echoes and rhymes.
你会看到很多回声和韵律。
But there'll be slight oddities and
但会有一些轻微的怪异之处。
differences in a real time system like that, if that makes sense.
在这样一个实时系统中会有差异，如果这话说得通的话。
>> Yeah, great. Thank you, Mike.
好的，太好了。谢谢你，迈克。
Tao, how do you feel about
Tao，你对此怎么看？
this merging of internet with the automotive environment.
这种互联网与汽车环境的融合。
One of the questions that we've been asking
我们一直在问的一个问题。
is the clearly automotive in the automotive space.
是汽车领域中明显的汽车产业。
There's a really important security of indication, encryption requirements.
现在有一个非常重要的安全性指标，那就是加密要求。
And now the automotive industry is looking at internet technologies.
现在汽车行业正在关注互联网技术。
is do you think that would be sufficient?
是你认为那会足够吗？
Or do we need to work on different approaches that suit
我们是否需要采取不同的方法来适应
the automotive space better?
汽车领域更好？
>> Yeah, I think that's a very, very important question.
是的，我认为这是一个非常非常重要的问题。
[COUGH] So I think what we do need a lot of help
（咳嗽）所以我认为我们确实需要很多帮助。
from the internet community in this area insecurity and trustworthiness.
在这个领域，来自互联网社区的不安全感和可信度问题。
But I think automotive do bring in a very unique
但我认为汽车确实带来了一种非常独特的
set of challenges that even today's, state of the art security
一套挑战，即使是今天的最先进的安全技术也可能难以应对。
paradigm that we use for the internet [COUGH] may not be adequate enough.
我们用于互联网的范式可能还不够充分。
So [COUGH] several examples and
因此，几个例子以及
incidence response.
事件响应。
And think about sort of the hallway respond to incidences and
并思考如何在过道中对事件进行响应。
to our computers.
对我们的电脑。
You got a virus on the computer.
你的电脑中了病毒。
So what do you do, right?
那你该怎么办呢？
You typically send it to some expert and the expert shutting down and
你通常会把它送到某个专家那里，然后专家会关闭设备并
trying to diagnose them to replace software, hardware, whenever necessary and
尝试诊断它们以便在必要时替换软件、硬件，以及
reboot it, and you just simply cannot do that to a car.
重启它，但你就是不能这样对待一辆汽车。
And so [COUGH] then the question is what do you do?
那么问题就是你该怎么办？
And I don't think we have a good answer yet.
我认为我们还没有一个好的答案。
So that is and that is an area I think people can build upon
所以那是一个我认为人们可以在其基础上发展的领域。
what we have and to really sort of come up with solutions for automotive.
我们所拥有的，以及真正提出针对汽车行业的解决方案。
I'll give you another example that actually there are a quite I have quite
我再给你举一个实际的例子，其实有很多，我有很多。
a long list of this.
一长串这样的例子。
Another example of sort of the uniqueness abroad to bide automotives,
又一个独特的例子，关于在国外等待汽车的情况。
well, no sort of automotives are very sensitive to cost, and the processing
在成本方面，几乎没有哪种汽车不敏感，而且加工过程...
powers as a result on the automotive side are usually relatively more restricted.
在汽车方面，由于此结果，通常权力相对更受限制。
And then for example our computers and cellphones and however at
我们的电脑和手机等设备虽然如此，但在...
the same time our car needs to run on the road for an average of 14 years.
同样的，我们的汽车平均需要在道路上行驶14年。
So that's a long lifespan.
所以这是一个很长的使用寿命。
And security has this thing about, it goes out of date very quickly so
而且安全性有这样一个特点，它很快就会过时。
you need to catch up this security software all the time.
你需要一直更新这个安全软件。
Right, you need to update it to counter the more sort of advanced threats.
对，你需要更新它来对抗那些更高级的威胁。
And over that long span of lifespan,
在那么长的生命周期里，
there is real sort of a high probabilities that sometime down the road.
在将来的某个时刻，真的有很高的可能性。
Your new security software may not be such that your hardware on the corner may be
您的新安全软件可能不适用于您即将过时的硬件。
too outdated to support your security software updates.
那么您的安全软件更新可能无法支持过于过时的硬件。
And then what do you do?
那么你接下来该怎么办呢？
Right in theory, you could make the hardware sort of plug and play.
理论上来说，你可以使硬件支持即插即用。
You could swap them but nobody wants to do that, right.
你可以交换它们，但没人愿意那么做，对吧。
That's a hustle.
这是一种套路。
That's a reputation hedge.
这是一种名誉风险防范措施。
That creates inconvenience, that creates fear in the driver's minds,
这造成了不便，也在司机的心中引起了恐惧，
like what's going on with my sort of device.
像我的设备到底发生了什么。
And so unless in a fleet environment where sort
那么，除非是在一个由专家团队处理更新的公司的车队环境中，
of a company have an army of experts handling their updates, and
的公司拥有一个由专家团队处理他们更新的车队环境中，
even individual carmakers may sort of this may be difficult, sort of another area for
即使是单个汽车制造商可能会有点这样做可能有难度，有点是另一个领域的
example, AI is becoming more and more embedded into.
例如，人工智能正越来越多地融入到。
Cars especially self driving cars, and AI come with a slew of unique
汽车，尤其是自动驾驶汽车，以及人工智能带来了一系列独特的
security issues, especially when applied to automotive and
安全问题，特别是当应用到汽车和
people started to discover many of those.
人们开始发现了许多这样的问题。
And but overall, I think our understanding of that is still very, very weak.
总的来说，我认为我们对此的理解仍然非常非常有限。
And I think sort of a better understanding of how those AI based modules used
我认为对于如何使用基于人工智能的模块有了更好的理解将会是
in the car will sort of impose even more security vulnerabilities to cars.
在汽车中将会增加更多的安全漏洞。
I think will be a must.
我认为这将是必须的。
So, yeah, those are just some a few examples.
所以，是的，这些只是一些例子。
>> Thank you Tao.
>> 谢谢你，陶。
I have relevant question from the audience.
我有一个来自观众的相关问题。
He is asking about data availability for research in machine learning.
他在询问关于机器学习研究中的数据可用性。
It is obviously expensive, and also challenging to collect data
显然，收集数据既昂贵又具有挑战性。
from multiple vehicles to do distributed machine learning.
从多个车辆进行分布式机器学习。
Any thoughts on how we can help the researchers either
我们有什么办法可以帮助研究人员获得高质量的数据，或者可能降低这类研究的成本？
get access to high quality data or perhaps keep the cost down of such research?
>> It's possible to do, is easier to do a present with aftermarket devices.
可以实现，使用市售的后装设备更容易制作一个展示品。
As the vehicle provide their own network connection, get reverse engineering canvas
由于车辆提供了自己的网络连接，可以进行CAN总线的逆向工程。
that was mentioned in order to be able to sort of leverage to make use of that data,
这是为了能够利用那些数据而提到的。
but there's enough out there for
但是外面有足够多的资源可以利用。
number of vehicles where you can do that, that would be my suggestion.
可以做到这一点的车辆数量，这将是我的建议。
Trying to get Yen's to.
设法让他们同意。
And their legal departments to part with data for
让他们的法律部门同意分享数据可能会
researchers given the sensitivity of it, maybe more of a challenge, but
研究人员鉴于数据的敏感性，可能会面临更多的挑战，但是
by committee maybe respond to that better than I.
委员会或许能比我更好地回应这一点。
>> Well, yeah.
嗯，是的。
And as soon as it's somehow, I mean,
而且一旦它不知怎的，我是说，
that's, I think Venice folks know this quite well, as soon as you.
那是，我认为威尼斯人非常清楚，一旦你。
Are taking data from real customers in the field.
正在从现场的真实客户那里获取数据。
There's always that chance that you can D anonymize it if you're clever and
总有可能，如果你足够聪明，你可以将数据重新识别。
then you're gonna do sort of legal and privacy sort of landmines.
那么你将会遇到某种法律和隐私方面的雷区。
One thing I would highlight, I don't just use University of Michigan as an example.
我想强调的一点是，我举例子并不仅仅使用密歇根大学。
With M city and they're not the only ones, I think Virginia Tech and
有关M城的事情，他们并不是唯一的例子，我认为弗吉尼亚理工学院也是如此，
some others have done this.
有些其他人也做过这个。
They've actually done research projects in the US case around like V2X,
他们实际上在美国的案例中进行了关于V2X的研究项目，
where the research project itself is just to get the beginning of
这个研究项目本身只是为了开始构建一个良好的基础数据集，他们可以利用这个数据集来进行额外的开发。
a good based data set that they can use to build additional
一个良好的基础数据集，他们可以用来构建额外的
use for additional research, sort of after the fact.
用来进行后续的额外研究。
And so I have seen some academics, where they've sort of funded and
因此我看到一些学者，他们在某种程度上提供了资金并且
done actual projects to just get, get that data and
完成了实际的项目来获取，获取那些数据并且
what's nice in that is they'll often pick a cart handful of mix and
他们通常会挑选一小车的混合物，这一点很好。
models so that they can normalize that data a little bit as well.
他们可以对这些数据进行一些标准化处理。
And that's what you'll often find if you just pick a Ford or gym, or Toyota.
如果你随便挑一辆福特或吉姆，或者丰田车，你通常会发现这一点。
The data is gonna be similar but a lot if its going to be.
数据会有相似之处，但很多还是会有所不同。
Sort of a bit wonky to the specific sensors or
有点对特定传感器来说不太稳定。
how the network is put together.
网络是如何组建的。
And so that normalization is always a tricky thing to accomplish.
因此，实现标准化始终是一件棘手的事情。
>> Right, thanks Mike.
好的，谢谢，迈克。
So another question I have to, I'm sorry.
所以我还有另一个问题，不好意思。
Did you have a, did you want to respond to them?
你有没有，你想回应他们吗？
>> No, I think we should probably go to the next one since there's a low on
不，我认为我们应该去下一个，因为现在处于低潮期。
time and probably more.
时间和可能还有更多。
>> Great because the next one, the next question Ted is for you and Mike,
好的，因为下一个，下一个问题是给你和Mike的，Ted。
in some sense.
在某种意义上。
So one, so the question I have is,
所以我的问题是，
so both you and Mike have talked about data coming out of cars.
所以你和Mike都谈到了从汽车中获取的数据。
And Ted, you're a supporter of open data standards.
而你，Ted，是开放数据标准的支持者。
And making all these valuable data available to researchers,
并且让所有这些宝贵的数据对研究人员开放。
to users, to anybody who needs the data.
向用户，向任何需要数据的人开放。
And Mike has pointed out to the cost of collecting the data.
而迈克已经指出了收集数据的成本。
And sometimes the fact that, those who want the data seem to
有时候，那些需要数据的人似乎忽略了收集数据所伴随的成本。
ignore that there's a cost associated with collecting the data.
忽略了收集数据所伴随的成本。
For example, the aftermarket, the old ways claimed the right to repair and they say,
例如，售后市场，传统方式主张维修权，他们说，
well, you need to give us all the data from the car because that's our job,
嗯，你需要把车上的所有数据都给我们，因为那是我们的工作，
we need the data to do the tuning and so forth.
我们需要这些数据来进行调校等工作。
So, our open data standards, a good idea and how do we implement them?
那么，我们的开放数据标准是一个好主意，我们该如何实施它们呢？
How do we go about creating these standards?
我们应该如何去创建这些标准呢？
So we don't disadvantage or
所以我们不会使某人处于不利地位或者
make it unfair for somebody, for
让某人感到不公平，对于
all the players to play in this space.
所有的玩家在这个领域中参与游戏。
So Ted I know you're doing a lot of work and you're applicating open standards,
所以泰德，我知道你做了很多工作，并且你正在应用开放标准，
I wanted to give you opportunity a little more about
我想给你更多的机会去了解一些关于~!@#$%^&*()
what your thoughts are in that space.
你在那个领域的想法是什么。
>> I am an advocate of open standards allow for more interoperability allow for
>> 我是开放标准的倡导者，这些标准允许更多的互操作性。
easier dissemination of data, as Mike was alluding to, it's not just the different
更容易传播数据，正如迈克所暗示的，这不仅仅是不同的
signals but it's also the variations what's needs some meditated.
信号，但也有变化，这需要一些深思熟虑。
The company said what's the degree of error with the given sensor.
公司说这个传感器的误差程度是多少。
What was the sampling method it was collected on.
它是采用什么样的采样方法收集的。
And so
因此
like a lot of them a number of OEMs are doing some fixed time intervals and
像许多其他的原始设备制造商一样，他们也在做一些固定时间间隔的工作，
clicking 100 or whatever sensor data points and that's great and useful.
点击100个或其他任何传感器数据点，这非常好且有用。
We answered a lot of questions, but it may not be able to answer a researcher's
我们回答了许多问题，但可能无法回答研究人员的
question which may be very specific.
问题，这可能是非常具体的。
And that's why we need sort of when we have something
这就是为什么当我们有某些东西时我们需要某种程度上的原因。
that people are comfortable for safety and security reasons, allowing something to
让人们出于安全和保障的原因感到舒适，允许某些事情进行。
run the vehicle, they should be permitted to do their own data sampling.
他们应该被允许进行自己的数据采样，以运行车辆。
They should be covering the cost plus a reasonable profit margin for
他们应该承担成本以及合理的利润空间。
the auto manufacturers to do that, because there's fixed cost and
因为存在固定成本，汽车制造商应该这么做。
we make the investment capital investment
我们进行了资本投资。
on the computer resources from the vehicle and the ongoing costs of bandwidth.
在车辆的计算机资源和带宽的持续成本上。
Those are real.
这些是真实的。
And they need to be smart about not just what data points they collect,
他们需要聪明地选择不仅仅是他们收集哪些数据点，
but how they do that collection.
而且他们如何进行那些数据的收集。
As I said, a lot of you are doing fixed intervals, and
正如我所说，你们中的许多人都在做固定间隔的工作，
that's flawed, or it misses a lot.
这是有缺陷的，或者遗漏了很多。
A lot can happen within those group that were doing with
在这个团队中可能会发生很多事情。
one service provider every 23 seconds.
每23秒就有一家服务提供商。
That's why because you miss a lot in 23 seconds.
这就是为什么你在23秒内会错过很多东西。
There's a dispute future curve algorithm which
有一个被争议的未来曲线算法，它
helps sort of measure like the peaks and valleys and
有助于某种程度上测量峰值和谷值，以及
find pertinent data that will most likely been more useful once off boarded.
找到相关数据，这些数据一旦离开原有平台后很可能会更有用。
You need to be able to have new logic, they can also respond to events and
你需要能够拥有新的逻辑，它们也能够响应事件和
under certain situations, like a whole another set of data points.
在某些情况下，就像是一整套不同的数据点。
So there's, you.
所以那里有你。
There's absolutely no way that automated faster can collect data that will solve
绝对不可能通过自动化更快地收集数据来解决
everyone's question.
监管机构、保险承保人，所有人都可以回答其中相当多的问题。
Regulators, insurance carriers, everyone can answer quite a few of them and
generate revenue from it by put their software in the cloud.
但在某个时候，需要有安全可靠的方法从云端放置他们的软件中获得收益。
But they at some point, there needs to be safe, secure ways to
但在某个时候，需要有安全可靠的方法来
let others in my opinion, but, as I said, I try to avoid the politics.
让其他人知道我的看法，但正如我所说，我尽量避免涉及政治。
I'm not trying to scare away auto manufacturers and
我并不是想要吓跑汽车制造商和
that's going to eventually come from the regulators, I believe.
这最终将由监管机构来决定，我相信。
>> Yeah, it as someone who's technical myself,
是的，作为一个技术人员的我，
I'm gonna stay agnostic as to what the right policies are and
我会保持中立，不去判断什么是正确的政策，
even if you talk to different OEMs they have.
即使你和不同的原始设备制造商(OEMs)交谈，他们也有。
I'll admit they have radically different points of view as
我必须承认他们有着截然不同的观点，因为
to how much they want to sort of control when and have.
对于他们想要在何时进行控制以及拥有的程度。
Sort of essentially ownership of that data.
某种程度上基本上是对那些数据的所有权。
I mean I can speak for before that our view is generally, it's for
我是说，我可以代表之前的观点，我们通常认为，它是为了
fleet donors it belongs that the the data is kind of theirs to control and.
车队捐赠者认为数据归他们控制。
We're fairly actively looking at ways that the data can be shared within
我们正在积极探索数据在内部共享的方式。
the context of the privacy principles that we as an industry have adopted.
这确实是关于尊重客户的能力，遵守我们作为一个行业所采纳的隐私原则的背景。
Which really it's about respecting customer's ability to
这确实是关于尊重客户的能力，
kind of decide that data needs to be used for.
决定数据需要用于什么。
But back to Ted's previous point.
但回到Ted之前的观点。
A lot of it's a it's a heavy optimization in terms of how
很多都是在如何优化方面的重点工作。
much data is collected by what and for what purpose and
很多数据是由什么收集的以及收集这些数据的目的是什么，
there's a lot of effort, especially.
特别需要付出很多努力。
When you get beyond prototype vehicles into sort of the,
当你从原型车辆进入到某种程度的，
the mass large fleet to collect only the minimal that's that's needed to.
大规模车队仅收集所需的最少量。
To sort of get the job done.
为了完成工作。
And even retaining that I think one of our data scientists at one point
甚至保留那个，我认为我们的一位数据科学家在某个时候
had argued I want to collect the entire canvas in real time for every vehicle.
他曾争辩说我想要实时收集每辆车的全部数据。
And they then came and said we need, we need,
他们随后过来说我们需要，我们需要，
four petabytes per year of have to be able to sort of store all of that and
每年需要四个拍字节的存储空间来存储所有这些数据。
that's just the canvas to point that that's.
这只是用来指出那个的画布。
Typically sliced up in either one second or multi slices per second intervals and
通常按每秒一切片或每秒多切片的间隔来切分。
a lot of that data isn't really that interesting for day to day use.
很多数据对日常使用来说并不是那么有趣。
But to researchers, It can be of much more interest and
但对研究人员来说，这些数据可能会更有趣，
then when you compute the data costs to try
那么当你试图计算数据成本时
to do anything with that data collecting it at that kind of scale.
要处理那种规模的数据收集工作。
It's just astronomical and not practical.
它简直是天文数字，不切实际。
>> Great.
太好了。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
There's a side conversation going on in the chatroom about
聊天室里正在进行一场旁听对话。
the NBN security model, which I know our panelists are not entirely familiar with.
但在NBN安全模型中，我知道我们的小组成员并不完全熟悉。
But in the NBN security model, the data itself is secured so
但在NBN安全模型中，数据本身是得到了保护的，所以
the name is attached to the data and then there's a cryptographic signature.
名称附加在数据上，然后有一个加密签名。
That is attached to it.
这是附加在它上面的。
And of the people on the chat room are wondering whether we could,
而聊天室里的人们都在想我们是否可以，
given that security model.
绕过云端，然后就不必依赖那种安全模式。
We can bypass the cloud and then not rely on security
我们可以绕过云端，然后就不必依赖那种安全模式。
mechanisms provided, by the cloud and then simply have the data.
提供的机制，通过云端，然后简单地拥有数据。
I'll go to researchers directly.
我将直接去找研究人员。
But I'll let the conversation go on for a little more.
但我会让对话再进行一会儿。
So I'm thinking this was this was really nice and.
所以我在想这真的很不错。
The other NDN related point here is to
这里另一个与NDN相关的要点是要。
Ted's point about standardizing the data.
泰德关于标准化数据的观点。
It comes to standardizing the data names and this is very much an NDN.
它涉及到标准化数据名称，这在很大程度上是一个NDN的特点。
Topic where in NDN, the focus of networking is around naming the data and
在NDN中，网络的焦点集中在命名数据上，
not naming the endpoint where you can retrieve it.
不命名你可以检索它的终端位置。
And it seems to me that there's a nice collaboration opportunity here
似乎在这里有一个很好的合作机会。
to look at how the Indian naming works.
探讨印度命名体系是如何运作的。
And create name spaces that could be derived
以及创建可以派生的命名空间。
from standardizing the data, that could be obtained from vehicles.
从标准化可以从车辆中获取的数据。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
So we're coming closer to the end, and
所以我们正在接近尾声，
I wanted to first give an opportunity to the panelists,
我首先想给小组成员一个机会，
to see if there's any questions that you guys wanted to ask each other.
在我提出最后一个问题之前，看看你们是否有想要互相提问的问题。
Before I throw in one final question.
在我提出最后一个问题之前。
Given what you've heard from everybody, go ahead Teddy.
根据你从大家那里听到的，继续吧，泰迪。
>> Well sort of ties into the NDN thing you're talking about.
这在某种程度上与你谈到的NDN事情有关。
So, and sort of an earlier question as far as
那么，这也在某种程度上是一个关于早期问题的讨论，至于
automotive Ethernet, and sort of.
汽车以太网，以及相关的内容。
And you're also asking how the, this community can potentially help automotive
您还在询问这个社区如何可能帮助汽车行业。
manufacturers there is cost associated with all this that they're trying
制造商们正在努力解决与所有这些相关的成本问题。
to balance against, sort of capabilities, security, all these things.
为了平衡这些功能、安全性以及所有这些因素。
I want to see these patches take place in the vehicle.
我希望看到这些补丁在车辆中得到应用。
I realize this may take some time and some evolution because I've like to see
我意识到这可能需要一些时间和一些演变，因为我想看到
currently the most vehicles operate on can and other other bus networks.
目前，大多数车辆运行在CAN和其他总线网络上。
That is very limited bandwidth.
这是非常有限的带宽。
Its broadcast is a trusted network.
它的广播是一个可信赖的网络。
Anything can impersonate anything else,
任何事物都可以冒充其他事物，
which is not a good thing if you can break into that network.
如果你能闯入那个网络，这并不是一件好事。
So I like to us to see move closer to
所以我希望我们能够更近一步地看到~!@#$%^&*()
Ethernet sign messages not encrypted and
以太网信号消息未加密并且~!@#$%^&*()
then so that you know you can't have people sort of other devices that can.
那么你就知道了，你不能让其他设备这样可以。
Be compromised find their way or apps or whatever find their way in there and
被破坏，找到它们的方式，或者是应用程序或者别的什么东西，找到它们进入那里的方式，并且
be able to sort of eavesdrop in and send.
能够以某种方式偷听进来并发送。
Bogus instructions cuz that's futurist so I think that anyway,
虚假的指令，因为那是未来主义的，所以我认为无论如何。
I'd like to sort of encourage further dialogue with
我想要在某种程度上鼓励进一步的对话。
NSD community and an auto manufacturers and
NSD社区和汽车制造商。
to sort of Lend them your expertise.
向他们提供你的专业知识。
Looking at town now, hopefully sort of jumped in on that.
现在看这个小镇，希望已经有点介入其中了。
>> Did you want to jump in?
>> 你想要加入吗？
>> I thought that was a very good thought.
>> 我认为那是一个非常好的想法。
And so I don't have anything further to add there.
所以我没有更多要补充的了。
I was just wondering I have sort of a related question I was just wondering.
我只是在想，我有一个有点相关的问题，我只是好奇。
I do agree that standardisation is important.
我确实同意标准化是重要的。
And for data and the sharing of the data will be helpful.
对于数据以及数据共享将会是有帮助的。
I do recognize sort of the challenges that you're doing that and
我确实认识到你在做这些事情时所面临的挑战。
the privacy and the cost and everything.
隐私、成本以及其他所有相关事宜。
And so I'm wondering whether it makes sense,
因此，我在思考这是否有意义，
for example, for a fund, a neutral entity.
例如，对于一个基金来说，一个中立的实体。
To host the data so you can sort of anonymize the data,
托管数据，以便您可以对数据进行匿名处理，
trying to get rid of the identifying information that
试图去除能够识别身份的信息，
will sort of implicate any car maker, particular car models or so on.
将某种程度上涉及任何汽车制造商，特定车型等。
And so that neutral entity can host the data and then provide
因此，那个中立实体可以托管数据，然后提供
the aggregation of the data to users.
数据的聚合提供给用户。
So that data may not only be useful for researchers, but also be very useful for
因此，数据不仅对研究人员有用，而且对于
validating the vehicle performance, especially autonomous cars.
确保车辆性能，特别是自动驾驶汽车的性能验证。
As we all know, validating autonomous car performance and
正如我们所知，验证自动驾驶汽车的性能并
safety is still a big challenge.
安全性仍然是一个巨大的挑战。
And [COUGH] so we don't have enough data [LAUGH] to do for
因此我们没有足够的数据去做……
anybody sort of beyond the carmakers themselves to test their cars.
任何人，除了汽车制造商本身之外，去测试他们的汽车。
And there is like of standardization or even what do you mean?
还有标准化的问题，或者说你的意思是什么？
How do we even measure safety?
我们如何才能衡量安全性呢？
So, I think standardization and along those lines will be tremendously helpful.
所以，我认为标准化及其相关方面将会极其有帮助。
>> Okay great.
>> 好的，很棒。
Any comments from the other panelists on this one?
其他小组成员对此有何评论？
Cuz I think we're coming up to the end.
因为我觉得我们快要结束了。
>> [COUGH] standards, I agree.
>> 标准，我同意。
[LAUGH] I think data standardization is always important and talking with folks.
[笑] 我认为数据标准化总是很重要的，还有与人交谈。
It took SAE and some of the other organizations probably
它花了SAE和其他一些组织可能需要
numerous years to standardize on sort of data and
多年来对某种数据进行标准化，并且
all of the things around right to repair and all that.
所有关于维修权和所有相关的事宜。
And over over time, I suspect a lot of the other sort of
随着时间的推移，我怀疑还有很多其他种类的
data elements need to be standardized.
数据元素需要标准化。
It's just a question of what, when and where.
这只是一个关于什么、何时和何地的问题。
And then getting things into the standardized format.
然后将事物转换成标准格式。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太好了。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
So I think at this point, we can wrap up the panel.
所以我认为此时我们可以结束这个讨论小组了。
So thank you, Mike.
所以，谢谢你，迈克。
Thank you, Ted.
谢谢你，泰德。
Thank you, Tao.
谢谢你，陶。
Wonderful conversation.
精彩的对话。
Really appreciate you taking the time and
非常感谢您抽出时间。
educating us a little bit about the automotive world.
向我们稍微介绍一下汽车世界。
It's a fascinating space, I think.
我认为这是一个非常吸引人的领域。
I hope that more networking researchers will look at the automotive world and
我希望更多的网络研究者将目光投向汽车领域，
all the very interesting problems that are coming up.
所面临的所有非常有趣的问题。
So thank you again.
所以再次感谢你。
And at this point, I think I wanna pass this back to the [INAUDIBLE] folks and
在这一点上，我想我想把这个问题交回给[听不清]的人员。
see if IIya is back on line.
看看伊利亚是否又上线了。
And if you wanted to talk about fabric.
如果你想谈论布料。
>> Thank you everyone.
>> 谢谢大家。